CP Wong: Hi, Shumin!
Shumin Lai | NTU: PCB.
CP Wong: Hey, Jermaine.
germayne: Hey, hello, hello.
CP Wong: Hi, hi.
CP Wong: Quick, can we have a… can I have a quick overview, Jermaine on the breakout room? Breakout room?
germayne: Oh, okay.
CP Wong: Oss…
Easwaran Jayaraman: Good evening, everyone.
Byan: Hey, Jaya.
Shumin Lai | NTU: Hey everyone, I think we'll give, CP and Jermaine some time before we start class.
Shumin Lai | NTU: So, we think you can go and quickly grab dinner or something?
Shumin Lai | NTU: Shouldn't be too long.
germayne: Okay,
germayne: Okay, I think let's, let's just wait a bit more for more people to come in first. I think we have about 30 people.
germayne: So… Good to have everyone back.
germayne: Yeah, let's just, let's just maybe give, like, a couple of minutes.
Easwaran Jayaraman: Jamen, I'm checking the… Portal. I don't see.
germayne: the.
Easwaran Jayaraman: content.
Easwaran Jayaraman: Class schedule and attendance, it's empty.
germayne: Vishon?
Easwaran Jayaraman: Class schedule and attendance.
Easwaran Jayaraman: Under, NTU Loan.
Easwaran Jayaraman: Where we usually take our links.
germayne: the plus content is empty from NTULearn.
Easwaran Jayaraman: Yep.
Easwaran Jayaraman: And, under Module 3, I see self-study for Module 3 and Assessment.
Jagatheeswaran Rajagurunathan: Brian posted the link in the chat.
Easwaran Jayaraman: Okay.
Easwaran Jayaraman: That's for the attendance.
germayne: Jaya, okay.
germayne: It resolves.
Easwaran Jayaraman: Yeah, attendance is okay, but, course content?
Easwaran Jayaraman: And today's lesson…
germayne: No, I don'.
Easwaran Jayaraman: I mean, let me, let me check once again. Normally, we get this,
Easwaran Jayaraman: A link, right, for the course content.
Easwaran Jayaraman: today's lessons.
CP Wong: Jaya, the lesson, the lesson, link is in the schedule, actually. You can just go to the…
Easwaran Jayaraman: So let me…
CP Wong: Yeah, it's the same one.
Easwaran Jayaraman: Oh, okay.
CP Wong: Maybe I just copy it lah. I mean, I think by now, by now we should be…
CP Wong: It's the same eye, it's not…
Easwaran Jayaraman: Yeah, yeah, it saved. I was checking even yesterday, so I could not access it.
CP Wong: Are you cutting to end you learn, is it?
Easwaran Jayaraman: Let me redo it now.
germayne: Okay, so I think, I think we have most people.
germayne: So, okay, I think, I think there is this link that Brian shared for the attendance, so you can use the link.
germayne: Okay, so I think before, before we start.
germayne: I would like to introduce someone.
germayne: So, we have… today we have Xu Min, and… and Xu Min will be…
germayne: Shumi is also part of the instructional team, and she will be with us on Thursday. So both Shumi and I will be introducing both the module for 3.1 and 3.2 for this week.
germayne: And I think after that, Xu Min has some commitment, so I will continue with you guys. But for now, I think I'll just give the floor to Xu Min to introduce herself first, yeah.
Shumin Lai | NTU: Thanks, thanks, Jermaine. Hi, everyone. Nice to meet you. So, I'm Shumin. Yeah, unfortunately, I'll only be with y'all for today and Thursday, but, you'll be in the good hands of Jermaine soon and Bian.
Shumin Lai | NTU: So, a quick introduction about myself. I've been in the industry for about 10 years already. Always been in the data industry.
Shumin Lai | NTU: started out looking at big data, then I pivoted to NLP, which is where I realized my passion really lies. So I started doing NLP, way before even this whole GenAI hype that you see now. So, back then, I was looking at more, slightly traditional NLP tasks, like, topic modeling.
Shumin Lai | NTU: NER-style transfer, that's when we have more older models, like GPT, BERT, most of which you probably will use very much now.
Shumin Lai | NTU: But anyways, if you ever have any questions about NLP data science, or if you want to have a discussion about anything in this area, just feel free to reach out. I'll be more than happy to share.
Shumin Lai | NTU: Yeah, thanks, Jimmy.
germayne: Okay, yeah, thanks, thanks, Shumin. So, okay, so I think, I think here's how it will go for at least this week. So for this week, I will be covering 3.1, and Shumin will be cover, covering 3.2 on coming Thursday.
germayne: Okay, so I think today what I'll do is I'll start to set the tone in terms of introducing some of the basic foundation again. So, some of you might have already find this familiar, so…
germayne: you know, some of you might… it might be new to some of you guys, but I think it's… I think it's okay. There wouldn't be any assumption in terms of what I'm introducing. I will be introducing some of the core concepts in terms of probability, in terms of distribution, and we'll… we'll go a bit off some of the statistical
germayne: tests, you know, like hypothesis testing, as well as some of the properties in terms of the central limit theorem and stuff. So, we'll go through some of those. I don't think it's fundamentally new, so…
germayne: Yeah, so I think I will get started. So I think we have quite a bit of things to go through. I think some note… some note for you guys is that
germayne: I think some of the theory that we'll be covering today would… would be heavy, in a sense, if it's super new to you, and… and even if it's not… not new, in a sense, whereby if you have already learned it in the past, trying to
germayne: really, like, understand the… the concept might not be enough in 3 hours. So, just, just, just take your time.
germayne: to… to, you know, understand what we will be covering today, and if you have any further questions, I will help… I'll try to help… I will help you guys, right? The instructional team will help you guys. Okay? So… so… you guys should be ready, right? So let me… let me get started.
germayne: Okay, so hopefully you guys can see my slides.
germayne: Okay, so I think, I think in the lesson plan today, it is stated here that we'll be talking about probability distributions and introduction to statistics, but at very high level, there are a few things that we will want to talk about today, right? So, distribution, again.
germayne: I believe in Module 1, you guys should have some understanding of looking at things like your histogram, right? You understand the underlying distributions of data. So today, we'll be talking about some of the known distributions.
germayne: Right? I'll give a bit of…
germayne: insights into why knowing this kind of distributions is important, especially for some of the subsequent modules. We'll be talking about some theorem later on, right, to introduce more about probability, right? And towards the end.
germayne: We will try to consolidate this into your hypothesis testing, right? Basically, some of the statistical properties. And I will share some of the insights why having this understanding is very, very important.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Okay, give me one second.
germayne: Okay, so essentially, essentially, if you think about, if you think about what we'll be covering, in terms of, like, what probability theory is, is that we, you know, in a lot of areas where we are trying to reason about the world, essentially, it's just a way for us to quantify uncertainty, as you can see in the slide.
germayne: Right? And because things are usually not deterministic, we think about things in terms of, you know, what are the chances, what are the probability of stuff. So, essentially, you can see that probability, you know, a lot of things in the world are reason about probability, right? You have things like, you know, if certain events would happen.
germayne: If you think about financial,
germayne: you know, some of the finance… if you do finance, basically, you also think about what's the probability or risk. Similarly for medical, if you want to understand certain, you know, if you want to understand what are the odds of you getting certain disease, these are essentially all reason using probability, right? Which is why
germayne: I think to the contrast of Module 2, I think Module 3 is really much more quantitative in terms of really understanding how we can apply some of this theory in some… in each of the different fields, like economics.
germayne: static stakes.
germayne: even things like physics, and all of these are actually now, you know, going towards what we'll be introducing towards machine learning, right? So essentially, everything is just math, and it's math-heavy to some extent.
germayne: Yeah, so I think there's really nothing much, I think for the slide. So essentially, here we are just saying that, you know, if we always think about an event, essentially, when we say, like, oh, you know, an event of a specific outcome.
germayne: essentially a subset of outcome that we will be measuring, and within the event, there's also this definition of the sample space. Essentially, the sample space is just all of the possibility outcomes.
germayne: in an experiment. So one example here is that if you think about rolling… rolling a dice, right, you have the…
germayne: each of the outcome for the phases of the die, and then a specific event could be that, hey, what's the probability of getting
germayne: You know, just in, just all the even numbers, right? So this is just some basic definition. Won't take too much, won't talk too much about this.
germayne: Okay, so the first thing that we want to introduce is what we know… what is known as the law of large numbers, and later on, we will just use the notebook to introduce this concept.
germayne: But the idea is that if the number of trials increase, basically what we would see is that the observed probability from this trial will be very similar to the true probability.
germayne: And we will… we will basically see this idea where
germayne: You know, you will understand for a very fair dye, or a fair dye.
germayne: the probability of hits and tails is essentially 50%, correct? Everybody knows that it's 50%. But then, if, let's say, you chose to flip your die in a very small number of trials.
germayne: let's say, hey, what's the probability of getting hits? If you were to flip the coin once.
germayne: or twice, maybe the probability of getting hits won't be 50%, right? If you get the idea. But the idea is that if you think about the true probability for a fair die is 50%, you will start to observe this if the number of trial becomes bigger. If you were to flip this 1 million times.
germayne: You… and you plot out your observed probability, you'll essentially see that it's closer to 50%.
germayne: Right? So the idea here is that if the trial is very, very small, usually you won't really see the true probability, and
germayne: what law of large number is just basically saying is that if your trial increases, what you can observe is similar to the true probability. And the idea here is that
germayne: What we are trying to introduce later on is that many times in real world, you don't have observation of the entire population.
germayne: Right, so let's say if you want to know of certain… certain events, you want to know of certain opinion, you want to do a conduct… you'll conduct a survey, and usually.
germayne: In reality, you have limited budget, so your exposure to doing a survey will not be the entire population. So it's very, very natural that later on, you will start to see that
germayne: We want to think of ways
germayne: You know, we want to think of different mechanic… mechanics.
germayne: so that we can make some kind of inference using very limited sample sizes of data, right? Because
germayne: if today I want to know certain people's opinion, right? I go out on the street, I interview 50 people. I can't say that the 50 people represents the entire population, right? So I want to think of a way to make certain inference, and
germayne: Here, as an introduction. The law of large number is just basically telling you that, obviously, if you were to survey a larger proportion of people, what you get from that sample will be closer to the true outcome.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Okay, so I think, I think we will, we will start to do,
germayne: we will start to go through the notebook, and essentially in the notebook, we will just do a few simulations for you to understand empirically that if your sample sizes are smaller, you might not be able to see the true outcome. And again, the simple example that I just introduced is that
germayne: If, let's say, you were to flip your coins 5 to 10 times, you might not get 50% of getting hits, right? But if you were to flip your coins a million times.
germayne: you probably will see that 50% for heads and tails will be very, very likely, right? So again, this is to illustrate the law of large numbers.
germayne: Also, at the same time, we will be going through some of the central tendency, basically your statistics. If you think about understanding certain descriptive about your data, you need to understand what is the mean, the median, and the mode.
germayne: Perhaps you guys have already seen this in Module 1, because when you do your EDA, essentially when you're looking at your continuous data, right, or if you look at proportion data, or any kind of data, some of the basic statistics that you want to look at is basically what is the average, right? You'll be also looking at the median, and you'll be looking at the mode.
germayne: If you don't know what this is, I think it's okay. We'll be going through again in the notebook, right, as a form of a refresher.
germayne: Okay, give me one second.
germayne: Okay, so we're going to start by doing some kind of warm-up. We're going to start with part one first.
germayne: And I'm going to switch my… my screen.
germayne: Okay, so for the… for the exercises, the exercises.
germayne: is actually going to be linked in the schedule, and you should be able to see it's under the repository 5MData 3.1, okay? And in 5MData 3.1, you should be able to see that there's an environment.yaml file, right? And…
germayne: At this point in time, I'm sure you guys should already be familiar with how to install your Conda environment, right? So essentially, this is the Condar environment to install. So basically, you can do a Conda
germayne: EMV update minus F,
germayne: So this basically will be what you need to run in order to install the new environment. And your new conduct environment should be ML, right? And it should have all the dependencies listed.
germayne: In order to run the notebook. Okay? So for the first part, we'll just be warming up, we'll be looking at the first notebook.
germayne: Okay, so we are just going to start to warm up again, right, and really get some introduction to probability. So we are not doing any hardcore probability questions today, don't worry.
germayne: We'll just only be going through… Oh.
germayne: Wait, is it running? Let me see,
germayne: Okay, wait, something is wrong with my code.
germayne: Okay, so similarly to what I just described, we are just going to warm up a bit, right? So we are just going to see what the law of large numbers
germayne: means, empirically. So, again, just to re-emphasize, the idea of law of large numbers, from an intuition perspective, just means that, you know, if you run more experiments, if your sample size is bigger, you are going to get
germayne: The probability… the probability that you observe for that specific event is going to be much closer.
germayne: Right? So in this case, as we all know, for a very fair die, assuming you didn't… you didn't… you didn't do anything funny to your die, your die… sorry, not die, for a coin, assuming for a fair coin, if you don't do anything weird to your coin, your coin should always be giving you 50% probability, right? 50% of getting hits or tails.
germayne: And…
germayne: what you can see here is that, empirically, we are just going to do a simulation. We're going to generate, the different number of sample sizes, so we're going to see… you can see that we just increased the sample size all the way from 2 trials all the way to 4,000 over TOS, right? And…
germayne: empty.random.seat basically allows us to set all the results after this cell to be deterministic, so that all of the results will be the same.
germayne: Okay, so we haven't really talked about probability, this is something that we will be introducing later, but essentially, you will see, for those of you who already know, but if you don't know for this, it's okay. But essentially, for coin flip.
germayne: we can think of it… we know for sure that the underlying distribution for coin flips is going to be the binomial, right? We're going to talk about it later, but for now, just imagine that, for whatever reason, I know that
germayne: the underlying distribution for coin flips will always be binomial, right? And what we are going to do here is we can basically use the binomial function. So here, what we are doing is we are just using NumPy to sample from the binomial distribution, and here.
germayne: the binomial distribution actually has two parameters, which we will discuss in details later, right? And one of the parameters that we are putting in here is the number of trial and the probability of success. So here, we are just going to simulate that, hey, let's say, imagine if we were to flip the coin once.
germayne: with 0.5% chance of success, right? You can see that here we are just going to sample an outcome of 0. So what we are going to do here is that we are going to use this function in order to randomly sample from the binomial distribution.
germayne: And what we want to do is that we want to write a list comprehension, so you can see that in this cell, we are essentially doing a for loop in order to look through each of the elements in the array.
germayne: And each of the array you can see starts to increase the number of trials from 2 all the way to 4,000. So just imagine the trials to be the number of times that you are flipping the coin, right? And we are setting the probability of success to be 50%, because we know that that will mean… that will allow us to define a fair die.
germayne: Right? So what we want to do here is we just really want to count the number of hits count, assuming that we sample from the binomial distribution, right?
germayne: And we are just going to iterate all the way from… from…
germayne: 2 trial, 4 trial, 8 trial, all the way to 4,000 tolls, right? So we're gonna run this code.
germayne: And you can see that this is essentially the number of hits out of the trial. And in order for us to understand what is the probability of success that we have, what we need to do is we need to then
germayne: normalize this back to probability, right? So basically, for the first one, if we get two hits, we need to divide by 2,
germayne: For the second one, if we get 3 hits, we need to divide by 4, all the way, we need to divide by the number of trials that we did. And what we are going to do here is that you can see that we're just taking the entire list, and we're just going to divide by the total number of trials, right, so that we can convert them to probability T between 0 and 1.
germayne: And if you can… and if you see this, right, you start to notice that
germayne: You know, intuitively, we know that when we toss a coin, with 50% chance of success.
germayne: the outcome which we should expect to see the number of hits, must be 50%. And you notice that from this array, you can start to see that actually we are converging towards 50% as the number of trial increases.
germayne: Right? And this makes intuitive sense. If today I'm telling you guys that, hey, can you tell me what's the probability of hit if you were to toss 2?
germayne: Some of you guys, you know, you might, you might, you might flip the coin twice, and you might get hit twice. So does that mean that the probability of getting hit is 1?
germayne: It's not necessarily right, because the number of trials is really, really very small. So that's what we are trying to illustrate here, that typically as your trial increases, or if your sample size increases, you'll start to observe the expected probability, right? The outcome will be more, will be closer to the true distribution that you're expecting.
germayne: Okay, so you can see here that at 4000 TWS, you can see that it's actually converging towards. And obviously, you guys can try this in your own time.
germayne: You can expand the array to a larger value, and you can start to see that as the number of trials increase, you will see that the probability will just basically converge to 0.5, which is, like, 50% chance of getting hits.
germayne: And the next cell is basically just plotting.
germayne: And you can just basically see that the expectation here would be that if the number of coin flips increase, basically that the proportion of us getting hit should converge to 50%.
germayne: Okay, so basically this is just a recap of law of large number. Again, why is law of large number important? The intuition that we want to convey here is that if today you were to sample a few people, it might not be a very good representation of the entire population. And you need to understand.
germayne: Oftentimes, we cannot observe the full population, okay?
germayne: Now, can somebody tell me why can't we observe the full population?
germayne: Is it possible to observe the full population?
Gwen Lim: Lois.
germayne: Why? Why is it not possible to observe the full population?
Gwen Lim: Exponential cost assembly.
germayne: Right, so usually, usually, you, usually is, is, is, is cost, but even if money is not a constraint, you want to do a survey, not everybody would… would… would… would… would want to participate, right? So there's an ethical, there's an ethical reason, and of course, resource is also a reason.
germayne: Correct? I'm sure all of you, like, heard about, like, I think it's a very famous, side example, so people always say that, oh, you know, universities always do a survey after people graduate. So, usually they will call up certain people to say that, oh, no, how much do you earn from your first job?
germayne: So people usually say that, oh, you know, could we be buyers? Because the participants that participate, you know, might be inclined to share? Maybe if you have a higher salary, you will share. Maybe if you have a lower salary, you might not share. So essentially, the idea here is that
germayne: when you do certain survey, as much as possible, you want to get a larger sample size to ensure that your findings is a bit closer to the population. But the reality is that it's very, very hard to really observe the population, right? Unless you are a tech company, then perhaps you have higher chance of doing that.
germayne: Okay, so I think conceptually, this is… this is okay, right? So we are… I'm going to… I'm going to continue, right? Okay, so this is the first one, mah.
germayne: Oh.
germayne: Okay, so, okay, so what we are going to start to do is we are going to start to introduce some of the basic
germayne: the basic of what we call the expected value. So basically, the expected value, usually in probability, is where we really just want to
germayne: calculate what is the expected value across all the total outcomes, right? So in this example, again, this formula might not make any sense here, but the idea here is that we are really just
germayne: this is just the empirical… this is just the closed-form formula for the binomial distribution, right? So, what we are going to do here is we're just going to write a function here to calculate
germayne: the… the coin fit probability, right? So this is just a closed form equation. We will see this later, so don't worry. But here, the idea is that with this function.
germayne: Right? With this function, essentially, we can calculate what's the probability of us getting some… getting a number of coin flip.
germayne: Right? And we know that… so K is basically the parameter, and N is basically the number of trout, right? Later on in the slide, we will introduce the binomial
germayne: distributions formula, but for now, this function just basically allows us to calculate, for any given trial, what's the probability of getting K. So you can see here, if we set the trials to be 5, the probability of getting 3 is 0.3125, right? This is just a closed-form formula.
germayne: So, what we want to do here is that we basically just want to calculate, right.
germayne: Suppose if we have
germayne: the binomial distribution where I would want to flip the coin 5 times, with 50% chance of success, right, which is a fair coin.
germayne: I want to understand what is the probability from 0 all the way to 5 in 5 coin flips. And you can basically see that we can basically use this closed form formula in order to calculate the probability of getting the number of hits in 5 coin flip. And obviously, you can start to see
germayne: as we start to increase the number of coin flip, the probability of getting them in 5 coin flips is actually going to get smaller, right? Essentially, here, we are just basically saying that if I were to toss the coin 5 times, with 50% chance of getting hit.
germayne: if I want to get 5 hits in 5 number of coin flip, the probability, obviously, will be low.
germayne: Right? So essentially, here, we are basically just showing… showing you how to calculate the expected value, which is just the mean.
germayne: Right? So usually the expected value formula is really just the probability minus, divided… sorry, the probability multiplied by the outcome that you would like. So here, what we are trying to say is that if you were to fit 5 coins, what is the expected… what is the average number of hits? And…
germayne: The formula here is basically just a closed-form formula. We'll show the formula later, but essentially, binomial distribution has a formula where we can plug in.
germayne: Which allows us to calculate the probability for every number of hits, right?
germayne: And after we calculate this.
germayne: If you can see here, basically the formula for calculating an expected value is that we're just going to take a summation, which is just a sum.
germayne: we're going to multiply each of the outcomes by the probability, right? So, essentially, we are going to take the probability of 0 hits multiplied by 0, plus probability of 1 hit multiplied by 1,
germayne: plus probability of getting 2 hits, multiplied by 2, all the way until 5. That will tell us the average number of hits that we can get in 5 coin flip, okay?
germayne: So, we're going to run this code, Oh, sorry.
germayne: I'm gonna run the code.
germayne: And once we get the probability, we're just going to… we're just going to take a summation by multiplying it with each of the outcomes.
germayne: And you can see that this is actually 2.5.
germayne: Right? So what this means is that the average value of hit, of getting hit, the number of hits that you can get in 5 coin flip, is actually 2.5, right? That is the expectation.
germayne: Now, the beauty of this distribution that are known is that, essentially, we can actually calculate this, and I want you guys to go and try it out yourself.
germayne: So the binomial formula actually tells us that, you can calculate the mu, which is the average value. You can just basically take the number of trials multiplied by the probability.
germayne: Right? So it's basically, mu equals to N times P. So here, the probability, we know that the probability… what do we set for the probability for a fair coin is going to be 0.5. And the total number of trial that we are setting is 5. So 5 times 0.5 is actually 2.5. You can see, this is exactly the value that we just calculated.
germayne: So, essentially here, E is basically just the average value, which is mu, and because we know it's a…
germayne: binomial distribution, and if you look into the binomial distribution, the mu is basically n times p, which is exactly 2.5. So you can see that we can solve the average number of hits by calculating the expected value formula, which is the probability multiplied by the outcome, and you sum it across
germayne: All of the outcome. Or, basically, you can just take
germayne: Number of trial multiplied by the probability that you set, which is 5 multiplied by 2.5.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Okay, if you don't… if you… if you don't really understand this, this would make sense later, because we haven't really introduced binomial distribution yet.
germayne: But the idea here is to really just introduce the different statistics, right? The central tendency. Essentially, what I described as mu. Mu is basically just a mean. Okay, for those of you who don't know what I'm talking about, mu is basically this.
germayne: Okay, my handwriting's a bit ugly, but mu is basically like this. So basically, it's just the average. Okay? So what I meant just now is mu for the binomial distribution. Again, this is specifically for by the binomial distribution.
germayne: is that mu is equal to the number of trial multiplied by the probability. So this closed form equation basically can give us 2.5.
germayne: Okay, I'm just going to go a bit, a bit, I'm just going to move, move beyond. So, essentially here is just a recap, right? If you look at the formula, here we are… what we are just basically saying, X bar, X bar is basically your, your sample, your sample average, right? And what we are saying is that if you take
germayne: summation here. Okay, I'm going to take some time to introduce some of the math notation. So, in mathematics, you can basically see this, basically this is your summation sign, right? So, what we are basically saying is that for summation.
germayne: If I'm going for 1 to N,
germayne: What this means is that there's actually n numbers of X.
germayne: Right? XI. So what we are basically saying here is that we are going to take an average. This is a formula for average. And what this means is that if you were to expand this, it's going to be something like X1,
germayne: plus X2, class.
germayne: all the way until XN.
germayne: We are going to sum all of the X's, and we are going to scale them by multiplying 1 by 2, 1 over 2, and that's exactly the formula. And if you look at this formula, this is essentially how we calculate average, right? We sum everything within the sample that we have, n number of elements, and we just divide it by n. This is essentially the average.
germayne: And this is essentially the formula. And…
germayne: We are going to start to introduce this concept of sample mean, and the idea, again, here is that if I'm going to go out and do a survey, I'm only going to sample at most n numbers of people, right? I will not be able to
germayne: describe the population. So, typically, what we describe as the population average will be mu. Mu is typically the entire population's average, right? So, if today you were to talk to the entire Singapore, the entire Singapore citizens, and you're going to ask them of a certain opinion.
germayne: and you take the average across every single individual in Singapore, you're going to get meal. But of course, as I mentioned, many times meal is not accessible, and the only closest thing that you can access is X bar, which is your sample, okay?
germayne: Okay, so here we are going to… we are going to do the… we are going to do the… the… we are going to do a similar empirical experiment. So here, because we have access, again, to binomial distribution, right, the true population follows a binomial distribution, right?
germayne: So what we are going to do here, again, is that we are going to sample the binomial distribution, and this time around, we are just only going to sample 1,000 samples out of the binomial distribution.
germayne: We are going to sample again for the specific event, right?
germayne: the event here that we want is basically N is set to 5. Basically, number of coin flips is 5, and the probability of success is set as 50%. So basically, this is the event that we are talking about, right? The same coin flip that we are going to, that we are going to sample. And this time around.
germayne: This is the… this is going to be the population data that we have, but we are going to sample just a thousand experiments.
germayne: We're just going to sample a thousand experiments, okay? To simulate that, you know, maybe for coin flips, we can only repeat this experiment a thousand times.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: So, after running this function, essentially, we are just sampling from the binomial distribution a thousand elements, and you can basically see that these are all the sampled data.
germayne: Right, so essentially, we are just showing that for the first array up till the 20th, or the 19th array.
germayne: Essentially, you can see that these are all the different number of, hits that we get.
germayne: And what we are going to do is that if we can calculate the average.
germayne: We're just going to take… The thousand… we're going to aggregate the thousand number of hits, divided by the…
germayne: total number of length, which is 1,000. So, essentially, we are just applying this formula. And this basically tells us that
germayne: for the… for the 1,000 samples that we ran, the X bar
germayne: The sample mean is actually 2.47.
germayne: So, across a thousand samples, right, across a thousand samples, a thousand experiments, just based on this, our estimate of X bar is actually 2.47. And you notice this is actually, you know, pretty close
germayne: to the empirical… the closed form solution that we get, and we know that the closed-form solution is 2.5, right? Because mathematically, we can calculate it, and we know that 2.5 is the true value. So we can see that X bar, the idea of X bar is that X bar is always going to be an estimate of the actual value.
germayne: Okay? And later on, we'll start to introduce more and more concepts, and you will start to see that X-bar is very, very powerful.
germayne: Okay? The idea here, again, I want to emphasize, right, the takeaway here is not the math, the takeaway here I want to emphasize is that
germayne: for many statistical inference, you're always inferencing on your sample, which is X bar. This is your sample mean, right? And you will see later on.
germayne: that a lot of properties allows us to make some kind of reasoning on sample mean. Even though we might not know the true value, we might not know the true exact value, having the sample mean is actually good enough for us to make some kind of guess.
germayne: Okay,
germayne: Yeah, so essentially, you can also use, np.min, or you can also just do, the method from Fendas, which is, min.min in order to get the average.
germayne: Okay, I want to stop here first.
germayne: Let me give… let me stop here first. Anybody has any questions so far?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I just put out one.
germayne: Don't know how is it?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah.
germayne: Hey, Noel, before you… before I answer your question, you need to submit Module 2. Module 2 Summary Assessment, I think you are the only one left.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay, okay, yeah, I tried to, I tried to work on it, sorry.
germayne: Okay, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, don't work on it now, don't work on it now.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: pig.
germayne: Work on it after the class, blah blah blah.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay. Yeah. Okay.
germayne: Okay, so what is your question? Since you are here already, why don't you just read out?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, so, so I, I, I, actually, most of the time, I always assume that sample is good, you know, but today, I just, I just realized that…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: No, after your… maybe I've been reading all along, but I don't really think about it. But now that you, you, you, you, you're teaching it now, I'm just thinking that…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: How do I know that the estimate that I have, right, the sample, right, is actually good enough? Or how do I prove to people that it's actually good enough?
germayne: Good question. Well, we will discuss that later.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay.
germayne: Yeah. Hey, but your camera got one black patch, by the way.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I can have my own bad patch.
germayne: Yeah.
germayne: Okay.
germayne: Okay, so, won't answer the last question, we will come back to that later. We will come back to that later. No, now you are, like, now you are, like, now you look a bit ghostly, I think. You're, like, great. Yeah.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I don't know why, like, I also don't know. I didn't do anything to it.
Phillip Tan: You know, the cover, you need to open the cover.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Is it open?
Phillip Tan: Just now it was opened halfway, now it's fully closed.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Bill?
germayne: Oh, okay, okay, okay, okay, yeah. Okay, okay.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay, sorry, sorry, I didn't ask…
germayne: Oh, no problem, yeah, it's okay.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Incidentally touch you.
germayne: So Noel asked a very, very good question. Noelle asked a very good question, but I won't answer it yet. We will answer it later. But the whole idea later on is that, you know, we can only talk about X bar, right? But obviously, X-bar is not good enough, right? My X bar and your X-bar, if we were to…
germayne: hypothetically conduct the experiment. If Noel today decided that he just wants to go out and ask two people.
germayne: And let's say Jaya decided to ask to 20,000 people.
germayne: Obviously, our X-bar is going to be different, right? So later on, we will have a bit of, we're going to introduce a bit of concept to really understand how can we make some reasoning for X-bar, right?
Bhupinder Kaur: So, Jeremy, I also had the same question, but my… I think my question has a bit of a thing that, is there a standard we follow in… is it in statistics standards, or are we going to talk from a machine learning standard? I mean, if you could explain that also later, it'll be helpful.
germayne: Yeah, yeah, no, okay, so, just to answer your question, we are not into machine learning yet, not yet. We are still talking about… we are still talking about basic stats.
Bhupinder Kaur: We talk about stats. Okay, so from the stats standards, we look at that.
germayne: Yeah, we are all going through stats, yeah.
Bhupinder Kaur: Perfect, thank you.
germayne: Yep.
germayne: Okay, so… so the next thing… the next thing to introduce is obviously a median. Median is super, super important. Essentially, there are many, there are many ways to call the median. Some people just like to call it the P50.
germayne: essentially the 50th percentile. And the idea for this is that median usually is always compared against mean, right? Mean tells you the average.
germayne: And median tells you that at the 50th percentile, what exactly is the value? So you can essentially see here, the description is just saying that what median
germayne: typically does, is that if I have a bunch of people, let's say, again, here you can see that there's some example of the hit, but in a very simpler example, if let's say we have 3 people, right? 3 people telling me how much they earn, right? Let's say the first guy only earned a thousand bucks.
germayne: The second guy earns 5,000 bucks.
germayne: And the last guy earns a million dollars.
germayne: Right? Just 3 sample sizes. If I were to take the average here.
Jagatheeswaran Rajagurunathan: Okay.
germayne: If I were to take the average here, the average value, you will obviously see that the average value is going to be highly skewed by the last person, right, because of the extreme value. But if you look at the 50th percentile in this example, you can basically see that the 50th percentile is actually at $5,000.
germayne: So what this is… what this essentially means is that the… the midpoint is basically what we usually call the 50th percentile, right? The median, right? At the middle, at the exact middle, if you were to sort everybody from the… from the ascending order, from the smallest.
germayne: To the biggest.
germayne: in your… in your data set, and you're going to look at the middle… the middle midpoint, the exact midpoint, right, at the 50th percentile, right? What is that value?
germayne: So the reason why you want to do this is that this gives you a sense of the collection of, you know, it allows you to describe the entire distribution by giving you another perspective.
germayne: Okay? So just to emphasize, in this example, if I were to just look at the average, X bar here, you can see that X bar is highly susceptible to outliers. Essentially, if they are.
Jagatheeswaran Rajagurunathan: Jamin, is your screen sharing working?
germayne: Oh.
germayne: Yeah, I think so.
Bhupinder Kaur: Yeah, we can see everything he's actually doing whiteboarding also on the screen.
Easwaran Jayaraman: Yeah, I can see.
Jagatheeswaran Rajagurunathan: Okay.
Bhupinder Kaur: Yeah, we can see it.
germayne: I can… something, some, some admin, some tech issue? Are you able to see my notebook?
Jagatheeswaran Rajagurunathan: It's okay, it's okay, I will, rejoin.
germayne: Okay.
germayne: Okay, so essentially what I'm just trying to say here is that for the median, it's a very useful statistic, because it allows you to see at the 50th percentile what exactly is the value without it getting skewed by extreme values, which average will not cover, okay? And of course.
germayne: later on in the extra resources, we can actually go beyond the 50th percentile. You can also look at the extreme percentile, which is basically the 90th percentile or the 99th percentile. But that's out of topic for today, right? But the idea here is that median is essentially
germayne: the P50, the percentile allows us to generalize this concept, but the median is essentially the midpoint, right? If I were to sort everybody from the smallest to the biggest.
germayne: Right? And again, to illustrate this example, if you look at the, I think the government has released the household salary guide, right? So you see that the government usually will release the statistic in two ways. You will have the average earnings, the average household income across the whole Singapore, and you have the median, right?
germayne: And the idea here is that if you look at the average, the average might be skewed because of the high, extreme high earners on the end of the spectrum. But the median allows you to see that at the 50th percentile of the population, what is the salary that people earn?
germayne: So…
germayne: not going to go too deep about the function here, but essentially, this, you know, the code here is really just calculating the median from scratch. I'm not going to go through it, you guys can go through it yourself, but idea here is that
germayne: yeah, I'll just let you guys calculate this yourself in your own time. But the idea here is that there's actually a built-in method for you to just get the median, right? And more importantly, conceptually.
germayne: Median is always used along with lean to provide different perspective of the data that you have.
germayne: Okay, so for the, for the, for the last statistic that we'll be introducing is essentially the mode, right? The… the mode, you can basically just think of it as the most common, the… the highest count
germayne: of a specific data point. And if you remember, essentially, if you just, you know, in… I believe in Module 1, you guys learn about one of a way to actually, visualize your data is actually through a histogram.
germayne: Right, so basically, you can actually look at all the occurrences of your dataset.
germayne: Right? Usually, you have some kind of histogram. Essentially, the mode is basically the one with the highest occurrence, the count, right? So basically, you can see that this bar is basically saying that if my data has the highest occurrence, this is basically the mode.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Yeah.
germayne: Okay, so I'm just going to run the code here.
germayne: And… here you can see, some kind of description. If your small sample… if you have a very small sample size, the mode will be the accurate
germayne: Measure for the central tendency, and if you have larger, the mean, the mean, the median, and the mode will coincide, as long as the distribution isn't skewed.
germayne: Okay, so basically, you can just see this example for a very… for a skewed data, right, where we just sample a thousand.
germayne: Right? And you can see that actually, if your sample size is actually very huge, you can see everything to coincide here.
germayne: Oh, sorry, so we set the skill to 0, sorry, this has no skill.
germayne: Yeah, so if you were to set a data with a higher skill, so here we are just generating a sample data with a very high SKU, right, with a tail on the right side, you can basically see that
germayne: Because of the… the skewness of the data, essentially this would… this would result in the… the differences of the central tendency.
germayne: Okay? And here you can see another example is that the mode… the mode is actually the least impacted.
germayne: by the skill, right? So you can actually just see another property where, you know, if we were to compute… compute the mean and the median visually on the histogram, where we just sampled from the skewed data.
germayne: X. You can basically see that for the orange color line, we are basically calculating the mean.
germayne: For the green color line is the median.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Okay, so I think this is just,
germayne: I'm just going to continue forward, okay? So there's also other statistics that you can always use to describe your data as well. You also want to look at the variance, right? I believe… I'm not sure if you guys have been introduced to this, but essentially the variance is really just understanding the spread of your data, right? And from a formulation perspective.
germayne: that's going to draw out here. You can see that this is really just, you know, looking at the spread of the data with respect to the… to the mean. So basically, you can see from the formula here, we are taking the squared.
germayne: difference with the average. X bar here is the mean across all your data, and we just scale it by 1 over n. So here, it allows us to see
germayne: the variance allows… allows us to understand the spread of the data, right? So here, we are just calculating the variance from scratch, and typically, variance, from a mathematical notation, is described using sigma squared, so it's just your… your… this is basically your… your variance
germayne: Notation.
germayne: Okay, but just, just to, just to take note.
germayne: Let me see, let me see if it's described. Okay, just to take note, typically, typically.
germayne: Typically, for mean, we said that the formula is mu, right? So for… for your sigma, for your sigma formula, your variance, these two are usually typically used for the population, okay? And later on, you will start to see that we kind of differentiate them
germayne: between your sample data versus your population. So again, mu and sigma is always not accessible in reality.
germayne: Of course, if it's a known distribution, you have access to this, but in reality, if you are working with real data, you will never ever know what is the true mu and what's the true sigma, which is the variance.
germayne: Okay, so here is really just calculating the squared error.
Bhupinder Kaur: I have a question on that. Why do we say that we will not know it? I mean, if it's numerical data, ideally we should have that information available.
germayne: No, so, okay, so, just to be, just to be very clear, notation-wise, right, it's not known, not known in a sense as in
germayne: what you're saying is that we have the formula, right? Basically, you can calculate this, but…
germayne: In a… in a… in a…
germayne: in reality, when we used to define variance, you want to define it, it's always defined as the population. So what this means is that the… okay, I'm not saying that you cannot calculate variance. You can calculate variance of any data.
germayne: But the sigma square here, where we typically use it to describe the variance of the population data, the population is not known, therefore you cannot calculate the true
germayne: variance of the data, but if, let's say, you want to calculate the variance of your sample, you can do that. But we usually term that differently, just to be clear. So the formula here allows you to apply on any dataset, but
germayne: Sigma square, when people say the variance of sigma square, people usually describe it for the population. This is… this is in the context of me talking about mu and sigma.
germayne: Just to be clear.
germayne: So, these two statistics, Typically, when we used to describe something.
germayne: is usually meant for the population. Doesn't mean that you cannot calculate.
germayne: If that makes sense. Okay, but let me, let me go through first before, before, before it's clearer. Okay, let me, does that make sense? Can I, can I continue first?
Bhupinder Kaur: Yeah, yeah, please, please.
germayne: Yeah, yeah, yeah, let me, let me continue first, then you will make more sense.
germayne: Okay, so essentially here, we are just going through the calculation for the exact formula. You can see this is just taking the sum.
germayne: of the square.
germayne: error, okay, I'll just call it an error, but the squared difference between each of the elements with X bar, which is really just your… your mean of your data, right, divided by N. So here is your variance.
germayne: Okay, so I'm just gonna run this quickly.
germayne: And we can basically just validate that just using mp.var allows us to calculate the same difference.
germayne: And of course.
germayne: the standard deviation is really just a square root of your variance, right? So just a refresher for those of you that forget, your STD, your standard deviation, is just the square root of your variance. So essentially, it's just sigma. Okay, so this is your standard deviation. This is a notation for standard deviation.
germayne: Okay, so you can just see that this is the… the… the calculation. We're just… we're just…
germayne: Taking the square root here in order to calculate the standard deviation.
germayne: Okay? You can also do mp.sqrt, it's basically the same.
germayne: Okay, so…
germayne: what we are going to do now here is we are going to visualize the different statistics. We are going to visualize the mean, the standard deviation on the distribution. So you can see here.
germayne: On my notebook, The orange line is basically the mean.
germayne: Which is the average of the data.
germayne: You can see that the green
germayne: what we are basically doing here is we're just calculating the mean plus 1 times standard deviation, and the mean minus 1 times standard deviation, in order to show the range of the data, right? So typically, we use this for normal distribution, right?
germayne: in order to understand the range and coverage of the data, right? So you can see here, this range shows approximately 68% of the data.
germayne: Okay, so I think after I go through the standard error, then I'm going to elaborate what I mean by the… what I mean by the variance is not, you know, in typical sense, we don't calculate it
germayne: with respect to your sample. So there's also another concept of the standard error of X-bar. So basically, this is the… the standard error of your… of your X-bars.
germayne: So, you can see the notation here? So, this is the standard error of X bar. So basically, the standard error of X bar is the… wait, wait, give me a second,
germayne: Give me one minute.
germayne: Okay, so what… what we are trying to do here is that the… the… this specific notation of the standard error is what is not the standard… is not the standard deviation of your… of your data. So if you remember, at the… on the above.
germayne: we have all of your sampled data, right? X1, X2, all the way to XN.
germayne: Right?
germayne: the sigma X bar is not… is not this standard division, okay? The standard error of X bar is basically the… if you look at the sampling distribution, which is basically the distribution of your X-bars, all the different X-bar, right? This is basically the… the…
germayne: the deviation between all the X bars, because there's going to be many X bars, right? If I'm going to run an… I'm going to run my own survey, I calculate X bar, there could be another X-bar that you can calculate, because of the differences in the
germayne: in the… in the sampling survey that you are doing, right? So what we… what we want to calculate here is that the X bars, they will also have deviation between all the different X bars. So what we want to calculate here is the
germayne: standard error across all of the X bars, right?
germayne: So what we're going to do here is that in order to calculate this, there's actually two formulas that we can do it.
germayne: Right? So the formula here, you can see that X bar, again.
germayne: in order to understand the concept of sigma X bar, you can see that we are using a formula of variance divided by square root n, right? Typically, if you look at… if you look at the formula here. But I just mentioned that, in reality, you're not able to measure this X bar, right? So typically, what we replace this sigma is we replace it with S.
germayne: Okay? Because if, let's say, today I were to do a survey of N candidates, I could only calculate the standard deviation of this N. So basically, the S is the standard deviation of
germayne: this array, basically X1 all the way to Xn, I can calculate only the standard deviation of this. So then the formula for me to calculate the standard error of all my X bars is that I cannot use the sigma over square root n, because
germayne: population data, in reality. Okay, so basically that's what I want to convey in terms of the standard arrow.
germayne: Okay, I'm not sure if this is very confusing for a lot of people.
germayne: anybody, anybody, anybody actually understood this, and anybody understand what I have just described?
germayne: In terms of the standard error.
germayne: Wait, I cannot see your faces. Wait.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Yama, can you explain again about the XPA?
germayne: Okay, Vera, Vera. Okay, I, I…
germayne: Okay, wait, let me… give me a while.
germayne: Okay.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I don't understand why you have standard error. I mean, it's my first time coming across standard error. So, I mean, what's the purpose of standard error in the first place? I mean, what is it measuring? Why is there an error?
germayne: the standard error of all your X-bars. Basically, the standard error is just another way to describe your X-bars.
germayne: your X bar. Okay, let me, let me talk a bit about the X bar, you know, I want to re-emphasize the X-bar.
germayne: Okay, so the story is like that, right?
germayne: in reality, we are… the whole… okay, so, just to be clear, today, right, we'll be talking a lot about X-bar, okay? And the… and the reason we are going to talk about X-bar has two… has… okay, one very big… one… one very big factor.
germayne: One very big factor today, right, again, I'll give you guys an example. If today, I were to ask you guys to do a survey of how much people will… how much people earn, and let's say today, Noel, he goes out to the street, and he starts interviewing people.
germayne: Noel is only going to interview a finite number of people so far, agree?
germayne: Let's say I give Noel a fixed amount of money in order to go and find out, okay, can you help me find out how much does Singaporean earn? Given the… given finite resource, given that you are only one single person, given that you only have 2 hours, you can only ask N number of individuals. Agree? So far?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay.
germayne: Right? So, I cannot say that Noelle will interview the entire Singapore population. Noelle can only interview, n number of
germayne: people. And when you calculate the average salary out of your n number of surveyed people, it's going to be X bar. It's going to be your sample mean.
germayne: So, let's say, hypothetically, you interview.
germayne: 10 people, and you take the average salary, and the average salary you get is $4,000.
germayne: Now, let me ask everybody in the class, can I say the whole Singapore earns $4,000?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Nola.
germayne: I can't make that statement, right?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah.
germayne: Now, in a hypothetical sense, mu, which is the population.
germayne: if I can… if I can ask every single individual, which is not hypothetically possible, but
germayne: I ask 6 million people, and I take the average.
germayne: Is this the true popula… can I say that the average salary, let's say, is X amount?
germayne: Can I say… oh, sorry, sorry, let me not add any more notation.
germayne: Let's say the average salary that you calculate is MIM.
germayne: Can I say that meal is the correct answer? If I take the average across 6 million individuals, every single household, every single individual I ask.
germayne: Can I say that's an average? I can, right?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah.
Bhupinder Kaur: Yeah, if the data is not biased, then yes.
germayne: No, but it won't be biased, right? If I ask.
Bhupinder Kaur: Yo, if they don't give you the right numbers, I mean, that's fine.
germayne: Okay, assuming everybody gives you the right number.
Bhupinder Kaur: Yeah, of course, then you can definitely, because it's, again, you know, you've done it for the whole set.
germayne: Exactly, but for Noel, if he were to ask N number of people, I cannot conclude that, right?
germayne: So the idea here is that we are always going to be talking about X bar. Now, I'm going to give you guys another paradigm.
germayne: Do you guys agree that there's going to be different X bars?
germayne: Do you guys agree?
germayne: If Noel, hypothetically, were to ask, let's say, in an alternate universe.
germayne: let's say Gwen were to go and do her survey for her own X-bar. She's doing the same survey, she's asking people about their salary, she interviews the same number of people. Will the X bar be different? Let me ask you guys.
Hitesh shah: Yeah.
Easwaran Jayaraman: can be different.
germayne: Exactly. So, what we are trying to say here is that there won't be a single X-bar, because firstly, the concept here is that you are… you are sampling a subset of data across the population, which means that your X-bar is going to be different.
germayne: So there's going to be a different number of X bars. Agreed? There can be X bar 1, X bar 2, there's going to be a different X bar. The standard error here is basically just a way for us to measure the deviations between all the different X bars.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Whoa.
germayne: Just a way for us to measure
germayne: how the X bars would deviate.
germayne: Does that, does that, does that…
Bhupinder Kaur: I mean, can we… so, I mean, I remember vaguely this concept, but I mean, can we standardize it by saying that it's just a…
Bhupinder Kaur: a small error, or the kind of errors expected out of the whole sample set, because in the perfect universe, it will not be… everybody will not have the same set of data and the responses. Something on that line, can we define that like a standard error?
germayne: Not sure what I'm going with.
Bhupinder Kaur: The meant is that there will be, you know, chance… I mean, for example, there will be a chance of getting some error, even whatever we do, right? And then, and everybody will have a different chance of the error, so that's why your X-bar is…
germayne: Okay. Something you violated it, right? I… you know what? I… oh, okay, no, the thing is that…
germayne: Okay, let me… let me just close this first, if not otherwise, we won't be able to continue, okay? So, for the standard error, basically the idea here is that you want to understand the spread of the data, because if we want to… if we want to understand all the different
germayne: possible X bars, we want to think of a way to understand their spread. And this metric X bar.
germayne: of Sigma is a way to understand that.
germayne: Why is it useful? We'll talk about that later.
Bhupinder Kaur: Got it, got it. Okay.
germayne: We haven't talked about why is it needed yet. And from the sequence of the notebook, I understand that it might not make sense. So, the way that the sequence now is that we are just basically introducing the different statistics.
germayne: All I'm just telling you guys is that the standard error just measures the spread of all the different X-bars. Assuming that you have a collection of all the X bars, it measures the spread of X bars. How is this being used? We will see that later, okay? But just to take note this. And I just want to point out a very small thing here, is that the paradox of the formula here is that
germayne: To measure the spread of X bar, how is it that I can just use sigma? I cannot access sigma, right? Correct? That's what I've been saying. Sigma is, again, your population. Mu is your population. X-bar is not your population. X-bar is just your sample. And then, yet, the irony is that there's a formula here that says that, hey, let's just do this, right?
germayne: Hey, sorry, sorry.
germayne: Let me erase that.
germayne: So the irony here is that the formula is telling us to use this, right? I'm telling you that this is not possible, so this actually gets reduced to a new notation called S over square root n. I just want to bring this up ahead, okay? And S is basically
germayne: derive using your sample data, so nothing is from the population, so basically there's nothing you can use here.
germayne: Okay? So basically, that's… that's the point of the first notebook. So we are basically just introducing different concepts. Everything will start to come in later, okay? Just… just trust, trust in the process.
germayne: Okay, everything will start to make sense later.
germayne: Okay, I think we have taken 1 hour so far for our first notebook, so what we'll do is we'll take 10 minutes break.
germayne: Let's have… let's have 10 minutes break first, then we'll come back for this.
germayne: Okay? Let's come back at, 8.15.
germayne: Yep.
germayne: Okay, about 1 minute left.
germayne: Okay, let's, let's, let's continue.
germayne: Okay, so I think… I think before I move on, right, the takeaway for the first part of the notebook is that
germayne: A lot of large numbers, I think, is just a very relative… relatively easy concept. Important thing here that you should take away from the first notebook is a couple of things. You learn about some of the statistics that you can calculate on your dataset. Essentially, the mean.
germayne: The median, the mode, We learn a… we learn on the variants.
germayne: And we learn on standard deviation.
germayne: Right, so this 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, just to be clear, these 5 items are basically statistics that you can calculate on your dataset.
germayne: So if you have any kind of data sets, you can calculate the mean, the median, the mode, the variance, and the standard deviation. Now, I bring in some example, I think a bit too much ahead of time. I brought in an example of X bar.
germayne: I brought in an example of, Sigma.
germayne: Square?
germayne: Sigma.
germayne: Right, so we have these three items. We'll come back to them later, but they are… you can think of them as just a very special notation for your sample data.
germayne: And usually, and Mimo, I think we'll talk about MIM. So basically, all this, right, is really just about population and stuff, but…
germayne: Just so that the rest of you are not confused, mean, median, mode, variance, and standard deviation all can be calculated on your dataset.
germayne: Just to be clear.
germayne: Right?
germayne: In your Module 1, when you do your EDA, you can calculate the mean of your dataset, you can calculate the median of your data set, you can calculate the mode, you can calculate the variance, and you can calculate the standard deviation. That does not change.
germayne: The only difference today is that we are going to use it to reason on
germayne: your… your samples, your sample data, and we are using the same statistics, except we are going to apply them differently, and these are all the different notations. We'll come back to them again later. Just to close off, X bar.
germayne: is the mean of your sample. So basically, you ask N number of people, you go out and survey.
germayne: And you take the average.
germayne: Oh, not so… Sorry, Jonah.
germayne: Okay, sorry, where was I? So, just to, just to, just to close off, X bar.
germayne: It's really just the mean of your sampled data.
germayne: This, this, sigma square usually is just the variance of your population data.
germayne: this?
germayne: with a notation of X bar is your standard deviation of your X-bars.
germayne: Okay? And mu is really just your population. So we'll come back to that later, but this and the five items above, please don't get confused.
germayne: They are different, all clear?
germayne: Okay? All good, right? I'm going to… I'm going to continue on to the next section.
germayne: Okay, so… so essentially, right, what you're saying is each section, we are going to equip you guys with
germayne: more and more concepts, and each of these concepts will be super, super important, which is why I say that, you know, if any of these points you are very, very confused, please take some time to go through them, because
germayne: Each of these individual concepts is the basic foundation to understand
germayne: the end goal of today, which is really just your expert… your hypothesis, your hypothesis testing, essentially. That is what is important. But each of these builds up to that concept.
germayne: Okay, so what we are going to do in the next few slides is to talk a bit about distribution. We are going to go back to distribution again.
germayne: Okay? So if you remember just now, in our first notebook, I say that, oh, you know, there's a binomial distribution. So basically, right, the important takeaway that you need to understand is there's just two types of distribution, okay? There's two very distinct type of distribution. One is what we call discrete.
germayne: Right? Which means that each of the items are all countable specifically, right? You will see later some example. And then there's also a second type, which is continuous, which means they cover continuous values.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: And we're going to explore some properties between them, which are super, super critical, in my opinion.
germayne: Let me… See ya.
germayne: Okay.
germayne: Okay, so essentially the first type of distribution is really your discrete probability distribution.
germayne: So discrete probability… discrete probability distribution, they are basically applied to countable outcomes, right? So just now, the example, the coin flip, each of the coin flip, they have a… they have a specific outcome, right? Those are all very… those are all countable. And all of the probability adds up to 1, okay?
germayne: There are a few examples. Very common, common ones that you will learn in school will be the Bernoulli.
germayne: Which is, like, one single trial of the binomial. Then you have binomial, which is the one that we went through, right? And then you have your poison.
germayne: Each of them, they represent different things, usually used to model different events, right? Your binomial usually is all modeled for an item that has a discrete probability, which is one example, like the dice throw, your coin, your coin, your coin flip.
germayne: So basically, your binomial just now we mentioned. We're going to use one example for binomial, but essentially, the idea is that binomial has a few parameters.
germayne: right, basically one of the parameters is your N, another parameter is your P, which is the probability of success. So you decide what is the… the… the number of
germayne: trial, right? Like, how many flips, for example, and P is the probability of the success, right? And…
germayne: Basically, with binomial, right, you essentially can calculate the probability, and that, that, and I want to go through this thing with you guys, right? The key difference here, right, mathematically, I'm going to just write this down, this is super, super important.
germayne: From a mathematical sense, the function, right, later on that you'll see for binomial, the function allows you to calculate the probability.
germayne: So basically, this is the notation, right? F of X is equal to p of x minus… big x equals to small x. So what this basically means, right, is that if you give me access to the binomial close equation, the math equation, I can just basically pluck in the X value in order to calculate the probability of
germayne: That event happening, which is what you saw… what you guys saw just now, right?
germayne: if I have, if I have,
germayne: If I have a coin of 5 flips, which is n equals to 5,
germayne: I'm going to plug in n equals to 5, and I set the probability of success to be 50%, which is a very fair coin. It's a fair coin.
germayne: I plug into this equation, and I can just substitute X, right? X for any X value, I can basically calculate the probability of that event happening, and it will be accurate.
germayne: Because the underlying distribution follows binomial distribution.
germayne: Okay, just to be very clear. Now…
germayne: You can… you can make an… mathematically, right, if you, if you, if you were to convert these by performing an integration.
germayne: you integrate this, you become big F,
germayne: Basically, big F basically tells us the cumulative distribution, which is this.
germayne: So what this means is that if I plug into any value into big F,
germayne: For binomial distribution, after I perform an integral transformation, I can calculate the cumulative distribution, which is, let's say, what is the probability of getting 5 hits and below?
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Why I want to… why I'm talking about this is later on, you will see it's important. So the math part is not really important, but the point I'm just trying to illustrate is for discrete probability, the function essentially allows you to map to the probability.
germayne: Right? If I have access to the distribution, I can basically use this equation to tell me the probability, and it's very, very powerful, right? I don't have to write code to write the coin flip 1 million times. Essentially, I can just calculate
germayne: If I know that the event follows binomial distribution, I can essentially calculate the probability, and that is very, very powerful, because I know the probability. I do not need to run the actual coin. I do not need to flip the coin, I do not need to write a Python code to simulate the coin. I can basically calculate the
germayne: the exact closed-form solution for the probability, okay? That's all I'm just… that's all… that's all I'm just trying to say, okay? And small f and big F, right, basically is an integration, so this one is just an integration. I'm not telling you guys to do the integration.
germayne: But basically, if you do an integral, you can convert the formula for binomial distribution into this, which allows you to give me the cumulative distribution. So this is the cumulative probability, sorry, cumulative probability, right? Allows me to plug into any value.
germayne: So just now, if you go back to your notebook, I think we were doing… we were doing P equals to X, zero… how many… number of hits? 0.
germayne: We were calculating for number of heads equals to 1,
germayne: Et cetera, et cetera. And basically, we just plug into the formula.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Okay, I'm going to… I'm going to augout anybody lost.
germayne: Anyway, you guys get my point, right? You guys don't need to work out the formula, but my point here is just that for discrete.
germayne: Distribution.
germayne: the specific formula that you will see for each of the distribu… you can go in… you can just go in wiki, or you can just go and Google each of the distributions, you will see a formula. And today, we'll just be showing the… the formula for binomial. But all of them, basically, you have F of X.
germayne: And what this means is that if I were to plot them, or to plug them into the equation, I can directly get the probability. That's what I mean.
germayne: Okay? I erase this. Now, if I were to plot out the… distribution.
germayne: Just now, if you remember the coin flip.
germayne: if I have… If I set n equals to 5, P equals to 0.5.
germayne: you will expect your distribution to be something along the line of like that, right? I think it'll be something along… I think it'll be something like that.
germayne: It'll be something like that. And the intuition is that if you were to plot this on the plot, right.
germayne: Right? You will see that to get 5… to get 5 hits.
germayne: the success, the parameter of getting 5 hits must be low, correct? Exactly, correct? If my… if my… if my event is to just flip 5 times.
germayne: with probability of getting hits to be 0.5, the probability of me getting 5 hits in 5 trolls must be low. So the graph will look something like that, and this is the discrete graph. And what this means is that because I said F of X,
germayne: If I were to substitute X, it gives me the probability.
germayne: What this means is that if you plot it out on the graph sense.
germayne: I can just basically look at these 5, I look at the corresponding value on the y-axis, and that is my probability.
germayne: You guys understand what I'm trying to say, right?
germayne: So basically, every point on the x-axis, if I were to map it and then look at the y-axis, which is this formula.
germayne: it basically tells me the probability for that number of success, the number of events that I won.
germayne: And this is only specifically for discrete probability.
germayne: Okay, that's the point that I just want to convey.
germayne: Okay, let me erase this.
germayne: Okay, so… look at… if you look at this whole formula, if you look at this whole… this whole formula, this is basically the… the… the… what we call the closed-form solution for binomial distribution. Basically, with access to this formula, and basically what I… what I did just now is just F of X, I just basically called this a function.
germayne: If I were to plug in N,
germayne: Equals to any value, the number of flips, in our case it was 5. It can be anything more than 5.
germayne: P, because it's a… it's a fair quant we plug in 0.5, you notice that there's going to be a K. K is basically the small x that I said. If you can substitute the value to small x.
germayne: any value that you want, I think it will be between 1 to 5, because the probability of getting 6 hits in 5 shows is going to be 0, so it can only be between… sorry, 0 to 5.
germayne: Right? If I plug this in, I can basically get the equation for the probability of PX equals to K.
germayne: Okay, I saw that there's a question. Elvin, you wanted to ask me something, is it? Is it Alvin?
germayne: Adrian? Is it Adrian or Elvin? I cannot see, I can't remember who raised their hand.
Thue Leong Meng Adrian: It was me, he was me.
Thue Leong Meng Adrian: I… I wanted to ask, was it… conveniently you put the small X and the big X together? That's why it was a bit confused to me.
germayne: Oh, okay, okay, yeah, I just put it as K, but normally, normally people put it as X, right? It's because, it's in the x-axis.
Thue Leong Meng Adrian: Yeah, because I thought, how come both… what was the difference between the big X and the small X? So that was my puzzle.
germayne: Yeah, yeah, so the small x is basically value you substitute in your x-axis. So in the graph, right, let's say if my curve is, like, like that.
germayne: Basically, the small X is, like.
germayne: What is the value of the corresponding Y?
germayne: So this is a small X.
germayne: But yeah, in this case, it's Kayla.
germayne: Yeah, it's the same, it's the same. I mean, you look at the equation, the equation is the same. I just substitute X to be here, X to be here is the same.
germayne: P , n minus X is the same thing, but yeah.
germayne: Does that make sense?
Thue Leong Meng Adrian: Okay, okay, thanks.
germayne: Can write? Okay.
Bhupinder Kaur: So, why do we mention 0? Because probability cannot be 0, right? For K.
germayne: No, zero, zero, zero hits. You can get zero hits.
Bhupinder Kaur: Go ahead. Okay, okay, head check.
germayne: All right, yeah.
Bhupinder Kaur: Oh yeah, yeah, head's okay, yeah, additional.
germayne: Yeah.
germayne: So the K is not the probability, just to be clear. The K is the number of success.
Bhupinder Kaur: Number of success, yeah.
germayne: Yeah.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: So you can see that, discrete distribution, very, very convenient.
germayne: Right?
germayne: Yeah, so basically you can see that this is just a… this is just a working. So, the build… I think the endpoint here is that… couple of takeaways here, right? The takeaway here that you guys would want to have is that actually knowing the distribution of an event is going to be very, very useful, because it allows you to model it.
germayne: When I mean moderate, it means that
germayne: If today, for whatever reason, you found out that, I don't know, maybe a process that you have.
germayne: is binomial. What this means is that you can essentially calculate the probability. You know the probability, and it's a very powerful thing when you know the probability, right? You essentially have control of the event. I mean, sorry, not control of the event, but you essentially have some kind of…
germayne: You can do some kind of risk management, or you can really understand
germayne: what kind of decision to make for every parameter, right? But unfortunately, unfortunately, right, as you guys know, in reality, it's hard to know the distribution of your items, unless it's a very controlled event, unless it's a physics model that is well studied, or in operations, or in fraud, or in certain areas that are very well studied, and they usually publish a paper on the
germayne: distribution. I think that's very common in fraud cases, in finance, usually they have some kind of distribution, but if, let's say, you just want to model some random stuff, you probably wouldn't know the true distribution behind the event.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Okay, so obviously, obviously, we talk a lot about the discrete. Discrete, there are really, a few. We didn't really go, we didn't really go through all of it, right? We go through one of it.
Hitesh shah: arrested?
Hitesh shah: What is 8? How do you arrive at 8 in the previous ex…
germayne: Where…
Hitesh shah: divided by 8, the previous, 3 divided by 8. 8 is… how do you arrive at 8 if you are running 3 times?
germayne: No, I think this is just 3 over 8.
Hitesh shah: Yeah, so how do you get 8?
Hitesh shah: So 3 is a probability of 0 times head, 1 times head, 2 times heads. But divide by 8 means…
germayne: No, 3 over 8 is just 0.375, right?
Hitesh shah: Yeah, what I'm saying is, how do we get the denominator is 8? What is… what is the calculation?
germayne: I don't think I understand.
germayne: No, the, the… this is just 0.378, right?
germayne: I mean, you can convert this and then reduce it to refraction.
germayne: The 8 is not significant here, right?
germayne: You can just… Convert this back to fraction.
Hitesh shah: I know, I know. What I'm saying is 3 is basically on the numerator is, 0 times head, 1 times head, 2 times head, so that is how you get 3.
Hitesh shah: How do you… what are you dividing it by the number… 8 is what? The total number of outcomes is…
germayne: No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no. The point here is…
Bhupinder Kaur: So, okay, I think, I don't know, let me give it a try if I'm…
germayne: I love it.
Bhupinder Kaur: Correct. So, if you see on the left side, right, Hitesh, so if you see the probability of getting exactly 2 heads in 3 coin flips, so it's a 3x coin flip is 0.375.
Bhupinder Kaur: Which will be 3 times of 8,
Bhupinder Kaur: this thing. It's just a significant number saying, for example, if you… 0.375, how will you convert it into how many times you will get it, right? Like, in the sense, from a numerical numerator and numerator. So it'll be like, out of 8 times, if you flip it, it'll be only 3 times which you'll get it.
Bhupinder Kaur: So, that's what they're trying to say. I know you… in the sample, in… what they've taken is 3 times flip, but as a significant number, they're saying that value will be like that, because 0.375, if you give an answer, it doesn't mean anything in the point system.
Bhupinder Kaur: You know, in the decimal. So you basically… what you're trying to say is, if you flip 8 times, it's a 3 times probability you'll get it, basically. That's what they're trying to say, as a probability perspective. But the original is only 3 times you'll get it, but the op… in probability, you kind of give these kind of stats. That's what they're trying to do, actually.
Bhupinder Kaur: I mean, I don't know if I could explain it to you, but I can conceptually understand that, so…
Hitesh shah: Okay, very good.
germayne: Okay.
Easwaran Jayaraman: Three will go for three explosives.
Easwaran Jayaraman: Frederick.
germayne: Sorry.
Bhupinder Kaur: Question there? Can I understand.
Easwaran Jayaraman: So, get this A to 2 power 3 will explain this, right? You have, 3 coins with 2 ops.
germayne: Okay, guys, guys.
Easwaran Jayaraman: Guys, guys, guys, let's…
germayne: Let's keep, yeah, let's keep this, this conversion is not the point.
germayne: Okay, that, it's not, it's not, it's not important. Let's go on, let's go on first.
germayne: Okay, so I think, I think…
germayne: I think previously, where I was alluding to, from the… from the descript…
germayne: probability standpoint is that I want to prep you guys towards continuous, because the property of continuous, distribution is slightly different, okay? So again, right, the continuous probability is usually applied to uncountable things, so usually it's, like, continuous values, right? So there isn't a single point on the curve.
germayne: So, what this means is that, and again, again, there are some example distribution that we have. We have normal distribution, we have exponential distribution, we have things like gamma distribution, so on and so forth, which usually we use it in modeling in machine learning.
germayne: Okay? Obviously, normal distribution is the most common and most important one, which today will be the star of today's discussion. Normal distribution is this bell curve-shaped distribution that we'll be talking about, right?
germayne: Now, one small thing that I want to talk about is that when you have f of x, which is the normal distribution, right, this is no longer the case of plugging in x to give you the probability. The probability, however, cannot be
germayne: calculated from a single point. The probability from now on has to be calculated from a cumulative distribution standpoint. So, if you were to do an integral, convert this to big F,
germayne: Essentially, this function now will tell us if we are to substitute any value in F, this will now give us the cumulative probability.
germayne: of big X less than equals to small x.
germayne: Okay, so that is the key difference. So now, in order for us to reason about probability, we have to think about the area of the curve, because this is an integral.
germayne: Right? So the idea here is that when we think about area of the curve, it's going to be, let's say, at a certain point, right? And because the probability is the area of the curve, the entire shaded region of the… of the… of the continuous distribution must be equal to 1, because that is the probability.
germayne: Okay, so that's the important point that I just want to allude to. Okay? And later on, you will see that this is very, very important for us to understand all the concepts.
germayne: Basically, key takeaway here for continuous distribution, right, in order to think about probability, you're always thinking about area under the curve.
germayne: Okay.
germayne: I don't want to use the… okay. Okay, so before, before we go on, right, we just want to talk one last thing about central limit theorem. Let me… let me… let me, stop sharing my screen first. Let me use my own whiteboard.
germayne: Okay, give me a wahh.
Bhupinder Kaur: Actually, one more point, sorry, going back to the other thing, quickly, I think it'll be… if you do it in percentage-wise, right, it'll be 37 point… whatever percentage it was.
Bhupinder Kaur: It'll be what?
Bhupinder Kaur: 37.5%.
Bhupinder Kaur: So, if you want to see it as a percentage rather than fraction.
germayne: Are you guys able to see my screen?
Bhupinder Kaur: Yeah, okay.
germayne: Can you see the duck, right?
Bhupinder Kaur: Yes, Kath.
germayne: Okay.
germayne: Okay, so I… I'm going to move a bit away from the slide, right, just to show you guys, so now we are going to take a step back into the thing that we were talking about, in terms of X bar.
germayne: Okay, so if you remember just now, we talked about X bar, right?
germayne: You guys, you guys can see, right, my screen?
germayne: Is it big enough?
germayne: Is it okay? Can't see it right?
Bhupinder Kaur: Yes, yes, yes.
germayne: Okay, so we talked a bit about X bar, right? And the… again, right, can you guys remind me, what's the motivation about X bar again? Why do I want to obsess so much about X bar? Anybody can tell me. Or not you guys?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Because there's no way to measure true population.
germayne: Okay.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: They have samples everywhere.
germayne: Okay, alright. So basically, right, yeah, and you guys are right on point. So basically, right, we are obsessing a lot about X-bar because that's the only excess of information that we have, right? So what we want to do here is that we want to introduce central limit theorem, because central limit theorem allows us to reason about the distribution of X-bar.
germayne: Okay? And if somehow, magically, we know that the distribution of X bar
germayne: then, essentially, that unlocks a lot of things for us, as you guys can see, right? If you know what is that distribution, if you know about the distribution of your data. So basically, right.
germayne: What central limit theorem tells us is that
germayne: It doesn't really matter… okay, let me, let me take a step back again.
germayne: So, in order to calculate X bar, I'm gonna erase this.
germayne: So let's say we have some kind of data X.
germayne: Let me just draw with a different color. Let's say we have some kind of data X. We don't really know what kind of distribution X comes from.
germayne: Maybe we…
germayne: Yeah, sorry, sorry
germayne: Why is my thing hanging?
germayne: Where, the duck is walking by, I cannot ride.
Bhupinder Kaur: Yeah, I was about to say, your duck is walking itself.
germayne: Yeah, yeah, but I… but my pen is not… Oh, wait a…
germayne: Yeah, but for some reason, my pen is not responding.
Bhupinder Kaur: I think your pen got disconnected, yeah, it just got connected again, I think. There's a pop-up bar coming on the top.
germayne: Okay, yeah, it's back. Yeah. Okay.
germayne: Okay, so the idea for central limit theorem is that it doesn't really matter what distribution the data that you are thinking about, right? So basically, let's say X is some kind of event
germayne: that we are interested in, and we don't know the distribution of X. And that's going to be the most of the case, right? But the idea here is what central limit theorem is telling us is that
germayne: Right? We don't need X to be… we don't need to know the distribution of X, but we know that if we take X bar.
germayne: Right? We know that X bar
germayne: Okay, sorry, the duck is blocking the way. Okay, wait, let me move it down, okay. So…
germayne: If you look at X, right, and you don't know what is X distribution, what central limit theorem is telling us is that with certain conditions, X bar is going to be approximate
germayne: Normal distributed, with Mew.
germayne: and sigma over square root n.
germayne: So basically, right, the CLT is basically telling us that with certain conditions, and I think the condition is the number of data points to be at least 30 or something, right? So CLT is telling us that if your sample data is at least 30,
germayne: right, based on the CLT condition. The distribution for X bar is actually…
germayne: asymptotically, normally distributed, which means that you can see that this formula will hold if…
germayne: X bar is at least 30, and it doesn't really matter what is the distribution of X.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Understand so far? And notice, notice these two, notice these two input,
germayne: For normal distribution for the bell curve, it requires two parameters. It's a distribution that has two parameters. The first parameter is really the mu, which is usually at the center point here.
germayne: Right? And we also have another one, which is the variance, which tells us how
germayne: The bell curve is spread.
germayne: So now, basically, if you can see, right, for central limit theorem, it basically gives us a way to tell us that we don't really need to know what distribution data
germayne: that we are looking at for that specific event, but if we just calculate all of… we just know that all of the different X bars, every possible X bars in the universe that we calculate, will always follow normal distribution, with a parameter of
germayne: mu, which is the… which is the population mean, and the variance will be sigma over square root n. And remember this formula? Who remembers what this formula is?
germayne: Where did we introduce this formula?
germayne: Who remembers?
germayne: This one? Pardon?
Bhupinder Kaur: Standard DVD.
Chieh Cheng Lai: era.
Bhupinder Kaur: G.
Teng Lee LIM: Era.
Bhupinder Kaur: Sure, yeah.
germayne: Exactly, it's this list, right? So, if you look at this formula, it's exactly the same.
germayne: It's the spread, and this bell curve is basically looking at all the possible X bars, right? So basically, we are saying that if you plot all the different X bars.
germayne: Let's say, hypothetically, right, we can travel back in time.
germayne: we do an experiment, we travel back in time, we do a different experiment, we travel back in time, we do an experiment again and again and again in an unlimited parallel universe, right? And you plot out all of the X bar, you basically see that it just follows a normal distribution, and the mean is going to be the population mean, which is mu.
germayne: And the standard, the error, the spread of all the X bar is just going to be this formula.
germayne: Okay, so that's why it's very, very powerful.
Bhupinder Kaur: So, so basically, we've already covered the variance, so that's where the X bar is, is basically already covering the variance, so we're not taking that variance as a factor right now.
germayne: Yes, and of course, in reality, this is just S over square root n.
Bhupinder Kaur: Correct.
germayne: Okay, actually, the duck is very annoying. I do not know how to remove the duck.
Bhupinder Kaur: So, by the way, my son saw your board, and he said the teacher also introduced this, and she got irritated, and she also removed the duck.
germayne: Awesome.
Bhupinder Kaur: He just sent that to me.
germayne: Yeah, okay? So, at this point here, at this point, your takeaway will be very simple. The takeaway here is that
germayne: If you were to go to any interview, and the interviewer were to ask you what is central limited room?
germayne: But right, you will know now that central limit theorem basically is like a way for you to say that regardless of what distribution we have, if we were to always take the sample average, the sample mean, we know that it will be normally distributed.
germayne: We still haven't got to know the why yet. Why is this important?
germayne: All clear, right, at this point in time?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So they're saying that no matter how hard, you will always tilt towards normal distribution?
germayne: Yes, that's what central limit theorem tells us. For sample mean.
germayne: So, which means…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Thank you, God.
germayne: So, which means… which means, if today you were to do a…
germayne: If today you were to… you were to go out and do a sample, a sample survey.
germayne: I think my thing is lagging.
germayne: You know, to do a sample survey, right? Basically here, if you take a… if you take the average.
germayne: You are… you are assured that these will always follow normal distribution.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Nice and blessing.
germayne: Okay, so that's… that's basically the key point. Now, we will go back to the… we'll go back to the exercise and to see this empirically, but from a… from a theoretical standpoint, that is the… that is the… the… the thing that is important.
Bhupinder Kaur: Yeah, and the distribution will be very, normalized, rather than having a spike, because we have taken the variance in count now.
germayne: So it will always be normally distributed for X bar. You can see, right, here it's just trying to say, like, no matter what distribution it comes from, it doesn't really matter, we don't really care. The average…
germayne: And again, just to be very clear, just to be very clear.
germayne: This is the distribution of the averages. All of the possible X bars, not your X. Just to be clear.
germayne: This is distribution of your X.
germayne: This is distribution of your X bars. It's very, very different.
germayne: So what this means is that we cannot say that… central limit theorem, just to be clear, I think the third time.
germayne: If, let's say, there's a specific event that you are interested in, we don't know the distribution.
germayne: Central limit theorem does not make that distribution normal.
germayne: Just to be clear, central limit theorem says that if you were to take your average.
germayne: Multiple times, all of the different averages. These averages follows normal distribution.
germayne: So what this means is that the takeaway here is that you can only reason about the sample mean, the average.
germayne: On average, right, you cannot reason about the actual Distribution.
germayne: Now, I'll give you an example. Again, maybe, let's say, Singapore, let's say the universe, or, like, the Earth.
germayne: there is this distribution of people earning some amount of money, right? There's some distribution. I do not know what their distribution is.
germayne: I do not… I cannot say that that distribution is normal distribution, but all I can say is, if I were to go and survey
germayne: 500 people and take their average salary. Their average salary that I calculated will always be normally distributed.
germayne: Okay? Just to be clear.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: But the X here is actually sample, right? X1, X2, X3, those are samples.
germayne: Who? They're here or here?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: the X123… X1, X2, X3.
germayne: Those are samples, right? No, no, no, no, no, no, don't get confused. The X here is just basically saying, no matter what distribution, don't get.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Oh.
germayne: This is just saying, imagine they come from different distribution, their average will always be X bar. It's not the X1, X2, X3, it's not. This is big X. The… the one that we talk about, right, usually notation, right, this one.
germayne: is small X.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So the notation here is the small x,
germayne: This is small X, this is big X.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: All these be eggs.
germayne: This is saying all the different X's, yeah.
germayne: But anyway, don't think too much about this, this is just a picture from online, it doesn't really matter.
Teng Lee LIM: So… So, based on this, CLT, right?
germayne: Yep.
Teng Lee LIM: the… The mean from the order average will be the true mu.
germayne: No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Incidentally.
germayne: the mean of all the average. Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
Teng Lee LIM: Yeah, sure.
germayne: District and the distribution, yes.
Teng Lee LIM: So that's how we get the mule of the population.
germayne: No, no, no, no, no, you will never calculate the meal, you just know that it's distributed that way. We will use that property later on, but you cannot say that… so I just think about it, so imagine you go and interview 5, 10 people.
germayne: you calculate their X bar, but you still do not know the mean word. You only know that this is
germayne: The distribution of this, right, is the… the… it follows meal, but you don't have access to this meal.
germayne: If you, if, if, if that, if that makes sense.
germayne: I mean, think about it, think about it, Tengvi. So, example, today, your boss asks you to go and interview 10 people. You have 10 data set.
germayne: You calculate X bar.
germayne: Can you say that you know the meal or not? You cannot, right?
Teng Lee LIM: No, but if I have a lot of X bar, if I can plot it out.
Teng Lee LIM: And it's supposed to follow a normal distribution, so the mean will be the population mil.
germayne: No, no.
germayne: No.
Teng Lee LIM: Okay.
germayne: So, so this part, right, is not… nothing for you to do here. This one, this part, right.
germayne: Later on, you will see, right, we are going to exploit this property to make some reasoning on X bar.
germayne: But we cannot use to solve mu. We need to… you guys need to just imagine, you can never get mu and sigma. I'll give you a counter-argument. If you get mu, right, then basically you solve your answer already, right?
germayne: But you'll never ever have access to that.
germayne: So you guys just need to understand that you'll never have access to mu and sigma, and the whole idea here is just our best guess.
germayne: to…
germayne: use X bar to make some kind of reasoning. We will never ever have access to X bar, to mu.
germayne: Got it?
germayne: So, X bar follows normal doesn't mean you go and plot out, because
germayne: Because there's maybe, like, infinite number of X bars, there's no way you can collect all the X bars.
germayne: Right?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: But your X-bar will tend towards normal distribution.
germayne: Yes, yes, yes, and we are going to use this as a property to do some reasoning later, but not for you to go and plot out and to go and guess what mu is, because you will never ever get access to mu.
germayne: Right? This is just a property that says that, oh, actually, the distribution of this X bar, all the different possible X bars, follows normal distribution with this mu. And we are going to use this to our advantage later on, not directly.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: My intuition is that because your X bar in the end, you know, you tend towards normal distribution, so all the formula can just use up, because in the end, everything will be all normal, mah, so…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Anything goes on?
germayne: Yeah, yeah, he has no way else. So, what you say is…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Let's do it ain't quite know what?
germayne: What you say in very crude way, yes, is correct. So basically, later on, because it's normal distribution, we're going to do a lot of things, and we're just going to say, oh yeah, just because it's normal distribution, therefore we can do it.
germayne: We are going to do that, yes.
germayne: Okay, so you guys are clear. This will set the foundation for… Many things later on.
germayne: Okay, so we'll go to part 2.
germayne: Okay, I'm not very sure if I can finish today, though. If cannot, then we will finish on… on… on Saturday, but let me… let me share my notebook again.
germayne: Vida… -Oh.
germayne: Okay, so I think I can go a bit faster, because you guys understand the theoretical underlying concept.
germayne: Yay.
germayne: Yep.
germayne: Okay, so we'll be, we'll be looking at Notebook, Notebook 2.
germayne: So basically, notebook 2, right? We are just going to go through the distributions again.
germayne: And we'll talk a bit about…
germayne: central limit theorem, empirically. So I'll go a bit faster here, because these are just a notebooks that you can just run.
germayne: Okay, so the first thing is that one of the… one of the… one of the continuous distribution that we have here is the,
germayne: radar.
germayne: Yeah, it's the uniform distribution.
germayne: So basically, uniform distribution, as the name suggests, all the probabilities are all uniform across every, every, every item, okay?
germayne: Okay, so the Gaussian distribution is basically the bell curve that we talked about, the normal distribution, and this is, like, sort of our best friend, because we are going to exploit this normal distribution a lot of times, okay? That's why it's good for it to be normal distribution. So, important thing here.
germayne: Normal distribution has two parameters, right, in order to define a normal distribution. You need to define the mu, which is the mean.
germayne: This tells you where the bell curve sits at, right? Just say it's, like, the average of the bell curve.
germayne: The standard deviation, sigma, allows us to define how widely spread the bell curve is.
germayne: Right? So basically, you can see…
germayne: standard… standard distribution, standard normal distribution is basically mu is set to 0, and standard deviation is set to 1. Okay, so this is the bell curve that we are… we always know, and they are called the standard normal.
germayne: So you can see, right, for normal distribution, if you set the mu to be 0, the center will be at zero, you can see. So this is essentially the point where most people will be at.
germayne: Right? And then the standard deviation of 1 basically tells us that the spread is basically
germayne: In a… in a unit of 1.
germayne: Okay, I'm going to go a bit faster.
germayne: Okay, so you can also plot the… a plot, you know, in your… in your… in your… in your typical histogram plot, you can actually basically plot the kernel density estimate. So basically, it just smoothens and overlays the distribution. So basically, this is the distribution that we understand, right, if we… if we plot these…
Thue Leong Meng Adrian: The other phone is speaking.
germayne: Okay, I'm just going to run these quickly.
germayne: Okay, that thing is running.
germayne: H?
germayne: Okay, so I'm sure you guys seen this in Module 1, I hope.
germayne: Okay, so you can see, right, because the normal distribution has a… has a…
germayne: has a mean of 0 and standard deviation of 1. So basically, if we… if we were to sample some data from the normal distribution, you can basically see that it should also be close to 0.
germayne: Okay? And the standard deviation is also close to 1.
germayne: Okay.
germayne: Okay, so, we already talked about central limit theorem. I believe on Thursday, Xu Min will talk a bit about the linear regression. So later on, as you guys go deeper, linear regression, you also see that it actually requires
germayne: certain condition for the error term to be normally distributed. So, actually, a lot of concepts will repeat the normal distribution again and again.
germayne: Okay? So… For this specific For this specific, example, Wait, let me see, huh?
germayne: Okay, so for this specific example, what we are going to do is we are going to sample 10,000 experiments from the normal distribution. So we are going to run the… sorry, from the binomial distribution, we are going to sample
germayne: 10,000 instances from the binomial distribution. And what we are going to do is we are going to plot out all of the output, right?
germayne: And you actually see that if we were to hypothetically sample from binomial distribution, which is basically, the number of trial is set to 10, 100, 100, 100 flips, right? If you think of it as a point flip…
Thue Leong Meng Adrian: Do you understand?
germayne: And the probability is equals to 0.5. You can see that, actually, these.
Thue Leong Meng Adrian: How many are you… you're eating?
Thue Leong Meng Adrian: Oh, I've still got ration. Oh.
germayne: Okay.
germayne: Wait
germayne: Okay, so what was I saying? Okay, so what I was saying is that you notice that actually this looks like a… like a… like a normal distribution, and the idea here is because we are… we are actually sampling here from the binomial distribution. The binomial distribution is essentially like a sum.
germayne: So, the whole idea here is that this is actually due to central limit theorem that by sampling 10,000 trials from binomial distribution, we're actually getting a normal distribution, okay? This is not… yeah, this is not, like, the intended one at the bottom, but if you notice, like, why is it a coincidence if I were to repeat it
germayne: 10,000 times, using binomial distribution, I'm actually seeing a bell curve here. It's because of central limit theorem, okay? Just saying.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: So I'm going to go a bit faster. So central limit theorem, right, as I mentioned, we can actually test this empirically. So what it means is that we try to artificially build
germayne: different distribution, we take their average, and we'll try to plot them out multiple times to see whether if they're truly normal, and you will see that it will always be the case, right? So here, we're just going to take, we're just going to use NumPy to take random data from X, I think. I believe X is from…
germayne: I think X is from your standard normal distribution.
germayne: Alright, so we are going to sample, 10 data without replacement, going to run this code.
germayne: And what we're going to do is we're going to take the average.
germayne: I'm going to run the function to just return the average, And I'm just gonna plot.
germayne: Right? So you can see that, you can see that actually here is not really that great, but if you were to take more sample, you will see that actually it will tend towards central limit tarot.
germayne: So we're gonna run this again.
germayne: And you can see that, oh, actually, central limit theorem works, right?
germayne: And what we are going to do now is, we are going to take a larger sample, and if you guys remember, just now I mentioned, the theory part for central limit theorem says that it's at least 30, right? So if you were to take a larger sample size, right, and take the average, usually the distribution will be
germayne: will be more towards a bell curve.
germayne: Okay, so I'm just going to run this quickly.
germayne: I think this is not that important. And in the next cell, basically what we are going to do is we are going to artificially create a skewed distribution. So, which means that the underlying distribution is not normal. So you can see,
germayne: This is the distribution, so mathematically, this is basically your X.
germayne: Oh, sorry.
germayne: So basically, right, this is your X. So imagine your X is to follow this distribution, which is skewed, right? What we are going to do is we are going to show that if you're just going to take the average, so here we are going to run this code, we are going to run a sample size of 10, but we are going to repeat this
germayne: 1,000 tons, which means there's going to be 1,000 X bars.
germayne: Right? So we're going to… we're going to sample from this distribution, we take 10 samples out.
germayne: calculate X bar. We are going to take 10 samples out, calculate X bar again, so X bar 1, X bar 2, all the way until X bar 1000. And we are going to plot all of these X bars, and you will see that the X bars actually tend towards normal distribution. So I'm going to show you guys
germayne: And you can see, voila! So basically, X bar 10 towards normal distribution, right? So, again, this is from a theory perspective, right? So just now, like, what, Tang Li was asking, oh, so do I use this to… to repeat the experiment? The answer is no, because you don't…
germayne: in reality, right, just to ask you guys, in reality, you don't do this multiple times, right? If today there's a budget given to you to go and survey, you're just going to do the experiment once. You're not going to repeat the experiment 10,000 times, right? So this is just an exercise for you to see that, actually, if you were to repeat the X bars, the X bars follows a normal distribution.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: So, we are going to repeat this instead using more sample, and we are going to repeat this a thousand times, so there's a thousand X bars, and you can see that… So, the idea here is the larger your sample, the better, right? Obviously, the larger your sample, the nicer the distribution is, but
germayne: Under the hood, the theory holds, as long as you are looking at average.
germayne: So what we're going to do here, again, for the last one, we are going to create a… we are going to create a distribution that has two pigs, right? Multimodal distribution with two pigs. And what we want to show, again, is it doesn't really matter what your distribution is, it can be some weird shape, white shape, doesn't really matter.
germayne: All you need to know is that by taking the average.
germayne: Right? Sample, take the average, sample, take the average, it will always be normally distributed.
germayne: And you can see, again, the results is normally distributed. So by now, you should be convinced. I mean, if this is not true, then the world will have not… I mean, yeah, lah, it has to be true lah, right? Just say, it has to be true.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: So, so, essentially, the takeaway here is that, okay, it's a very, very powerful mechanism that we, that we have.
germayne: Okay? So basically, that's all for… that's all for this notebook. And… and… I think for the last part, when we move to part 3, we will then… allow me to explain a bit… I'm going to tie in a bit why it matters from this. Like, all of this is going to be tied into part 3.
germayne: Right? And I'm going to tell you guys why it matters.
germayne: Got it?
germayne: Okay, at this point, anybody needs a break. Anybody needs 5 minutes break.
germayne: Don't eat it, huh?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So at this… until this point, my question's not answered, right? Was it answered already? No, no yet, no yet, not yet. No, yeah, right.
germayne: Not yet, not yet, yeah, not yet.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay, okay, good.
germayne: A.
germayne: Let me… let me share my screen again.
germayne: Okay, so Noel's answer not… Noel's question not answered yet.
germayne: Okay, so basically the whole point, right, I think I have already been prepping you guys, right, is that
germayne: In reality, we always have observation for sample data, and this applies for everything, right? Imagine even if you are… and I think I gave you guys a lot of examples today, if you're a pharma company, you want to make some medicine.
germayne: You want to do some clinical trial. Does your clinical trial expose to everyone in the population? No, right? So you try to design your clinical trial as best as possible to make some inference on the drug, right? If you guys remember when we take the COVID vaccine.
germayne: it's not as if it's tested on people, right, on the whole population. So, similarly for all of the medical trials, right.
germayne: they have some kind of clinical trial to do some statistical inference, right? So…
germayne: in… in tech company, usually we do what, what is called A-B tests, so usually we do a… we'll do an A-B test. So A-B testing.
germayne: Essentially, so it's just called A-B test. So A-B test… the idea of A-B test is actually very simple, right? The idea of A-B test is that
germayne: you have some kind of new feature, so let's say there's a new feature that you developed, right? And the idea is that, am I able to know if this new feature is actually better or worse?
germayne: Right?
germayne: If you were to… okay, and let me… let me ask you guys a question. So if today, right, let's say I have a… I have a graph. Let's say I have click-through rate.
germayne: So click-through rate is basically the number of clicks from user. So let's say, right, I propose a new feature. I say that, hey, you know, let's make the buttons and the page a bit bigger, so that people might be… might find it easier to navigate our app, and therefore, we will have higher click-through rate.
germayne: Let's suppose, right, suppose, suppose today is the 7th of April. Let's say I decide to roll out the experiment on the 7th.
germayne: And let's say our chart, our click-through rate is some value.
germayne: And then, let's say I propose to the management, I say that, hey, let's roll the features out on 7th, and then we observe the… the effect after. Let's say I observe the effect after.
germayne: Now, I want to ask you guys a question.
germayne: Do you think the effect after is a fair way for me to say that the item is actually contributed, the change in the trend, of any metric that I'm interested in?
germayne: Is it a correct way to say that my app is the… my changes is the contribution factor?
germayne: So I'll repeat my question again, so let's say I have a new feature. Let's say the feature is F.
germayne: And I developed some buttons. Let's say I make the button really big, I have some changes to the app page, and I decided to roll out the app on the 7th.
germayne: And then I monitor the click-through rate, and assuming that, let's say, click-through rate increase after the 7th.
germayne: Can I say that, because I wrote this out on the 7th, from 7 onwards.
germayne: the increase in the metric is due to my feature that I wrote out.
germayne: Can I say that?
Bhupinder Kaur: Yeah, you can, yes.
Josiah Ho: Yes.
Zac Ang: No.
germayne: Okay, so I want to ask the two camps, so…
Shilpa Kangya: This is the app-related change, what you added, right? Not the data-related one.
germayne: Yes, it's the app, and the metric that I'm measuring is from the company level.
germayne: So let's say again, let's say again, the click-through rate increased.
germayne: Right, I'm going to make the situation a bit more interesting. So let's say here is December, December 7th.
germayne: The app suddenly had an increase in click-through rate.
germayne: And I roll out the app on the 7, I just make this change on the page.
germayne: Then my question is, can I attribute the increase in the metric to my app?
germayne: If so, why? If no, why? So maybe those that say yes.
Bhupinder Kaur: One question, sorry, underlying assumption is the click-through rate is for UI UX, right? Like, you want to increase the click-through rate for… so that there are more.
germayne: Yeah, yeah, yes, yes, yes.
Bhupinder Kaur: Okay, okay, okay, because I thought, from a UI UX experience, you want the click-through rate lesser. So, yeah, okay, understood.
germayne: Okay, so let me erase the part. Yeah, so imagine the click-through rate were to increase. Basically, the click-through rate is just a metric, but it doesn't have to be click-through rate, it can be any metric, it can be revenue, it can be anything. But my question is, can I say that the changes that I made, that I released on December 7th, is the one that attributes to the click-through rate? Can I say that?
Josiah Ho: Yes.
germayne: Okay, so Josiah, what's your rationale? Why? Why yes?
Josiah Ho: Assuming that your button is bigger, there will be a higher tendency for people to accidentally click on it, and then all these will factor in into a higher click-through rate.
germayne: Okay, okay, okay.
Bhupinder Kaur: Better readability or understanding of the…
germayne: Okay.
Bhupinder Kaur: UI UX, you have.
germayne: Okay, Dan, who said no just now?
germayne: Zaga, why? Why do you say no?
Zac Ang: There can be many other reasons, so it's very hard to isolate out what exactly is the reason for this increase or decrease.
germayne: Hmm, okay. So, so the, the answer to this, right, is that
germayne: When you want to look at pre-post, right, it's not that… it's not… so basically what we call… what we call this is basically we call this a pre-post, because it's pre and post.
germayne: So if you're looking at the pre-post, right.
germayne: there are usually a lot of things that happens after, right? So imagine, imagine today on the 7th.
germayne: you could argue that maybe suddenly, towards 25th December, the holiday season, you know, it's a holiday season, so there might be more people using the app. So basically, the idea here is that if you do a before and after, you're not able to isolate the effect.
germayne: It's the same thing as, let's say, there's a supplement.
germayne: Right, let's say, wait, who work out? Who works out a lot? Josiah, do you work out?
germayne: Do you work out a lot?
Josiah Ho: Periodically, like, not a lot.
germayne: Okay, so let's say you work out, right? I give you some supplement, you eat it, and then suddenly you become very buff.
germayne: Can you attribute that your… your… your workout is because of the… the thing? You can't, right? Because there's a lot of factors.
germayne: there's a lot of… there's a lot of factors, maybe you… maybe you're… maybe due to your workout, maybe due to your diet. So… so the idea here I'm just trying to say, right, basically, is that
germayne: Usually, what people want to do is you want to have a very controlled way to measure your effect, and what people do is usually they do what we call an A-B test. So basically, you split into two groups, a control group and a treatment group.
germayne: And these two groups, they are randomly selected, so that both of them, one, get exposure to the intervention, one doesn't get exposure to the intervention. So in that case of the app.
germayne: What will happen is that on the 7, rather than I roll this out to 100% of the app user, I roll the effect of the button to a small segment of the user, while most of the user continue to use the app.
germayne: So what this means is that Anything after December 7th.
germayne: If there's an increase in holiday, holiday season, both groups gets exposure to that.
germayne: So what this means is that all the other effects are canceled. So you're only measuring the effect of the intervention that you're doing.
germayne: Okay? So that's the… that's the central idea that I want to introduce. And… and the whole point of this, right, today is that we're not talking about how to design A-B test experiment. But you notice, right, that if I have a control group, and I have a treatment group.
germayne: Right? Maybe I want to make some kind of statistical inference, right? But my treatment group is always going to be a smaller subset.
germayne: It's going to be a very small population.
germayne: And what I want to do is I want to somehow use the property of whatever that we have learned.
germayne: To make some kind of hypothesis test
germayne: To say that, oh, the effect is actually great.
germayne: Right? So that's the central ideal.
germayne: Okay, so that is usually what people do in the tech. Another, another, another example usually I give my students is, if you guys remember the election, I'm sure all of you watch election, right? You guys remember, like, during the election.
germayne: Usually, they will release the election results
germayne: Towards the morning, morning period, right?
germayne: And before they release the election results, they actually would do some calculation.
germayne: Alright, they will do some kind of calculation. Maybe they will take, like, a few samples from all the different regions, and then they will pull together and say that, okay, you know, based on the sample, based on the X bar, the sample mean, I can say that, oh, maybe the vote is like that.
germayne: Right?
germayne: So the idea here is that
germayne: If done correctly, you can make some kind of inference about the true conclusion.
germayne: Right? I mean, of course, in the voting example, we have access to Mula, right? You guys agree, right? When all the votes are fully counted, then that's the population, right? But the idea here is that, if I remember correctly, usually when they pull the sample, the results are actually quite close to the final results.
germayne: Usually, usually. If they pull the sample well, usually it's quite close to the final results. You don't expect the result to change very, very drastically. So the idea here is that
germayne: Why we want to do this, right, the motivation is that, firstly.
germayne: It's very rare you have ability to observe the entire population, even in tech company.
germayne: you cannot expose to the full population because it's going to be expensive, expensive in experimentation. So what you want to do is you want to sample some level of data, and you want to make some observation, and I think, again, later on, to answer Noelle's question.
germayne: You are able to then say that, what is the quality of your observation, which we will see later.
germayne: Right? You can also do statistical tests, basically it's your hypothesis testing, in order to test whether if your hypothesis is true. And the reason you can do that is because of the mathematical property from CLT.
germayne: Okay, so I'm going to… Okay, I think… Okay.
germayne: So, right, the first… the first thing that we're going to explore is what is called the z-score.
germayne: Okay, so the idea here is very simple.
germayne: I introduced to you guys the X bar, It's asymptotically normally distributed.
germayne: to mu, Sigma over square root n.
germayne: Right?
germayne: So what this means is that X bar, we know, is normally distributed, and for any normal distribution, we actually… we can do this thing called standardizing. So basically, we can make a transformation on any normal distribution. And if you remember, our good friend, the one that we mentioned.
germayne: We talk a bit about the… in the second notebook, we talk about the standard normal, right? There's this thing called the standard normal. So basically, we can have a transformation that transforms any data into the standard normal.
germayne: Right? And if X bar follows normal distribution, then we know we can apply some kind of transformation, which is called the standardization, to transform it to a standard normal distribution. And basically what we do is you just take your X-bar, you take away, you shift your mean, and you divide it by your standard deviation.
germayne: Right? So in this case, if we were to apply this transformation, this transformation will now follow 01. And why do we want to do this? Because the underlying distribution now follows a bell curve, where the center now is 0. You can see the center is 0, with the variance or the standard deviation to be 1.
germayne: Okay? So this is the first property that we want to explore.
germayne: Here? I'm going to continue.
germayne: Okay, so essentially now we can convert everything to standard to 0, 1,
germayne: We want to introduce another concept called the p-value.
germayne: So basically, right, later on, you will see, in hypothesis testing, essentially, what we want to do is that we are going to create some kind of hypothesis. Wait, let me see, huh?
germayne: Okay, let me, let me just share my… my doc again.
germayne: I'm going to take some time to explain the hypothesis testing.
germayne: And hopefully… The idea will be… will be better.
germayne: K.
germayne: Okay, I think you guys can see, right?
germayne: Okay.
germayne: Okay, before we talk about hypothesis testing, let me… let me… let me talk about… let me talk about one thing. Let me try to answer Noel's question first.
germayne: So right, based on what we are describing, right, we talk about X bar.
germayne: Right? And you guys remember, it doesn't make sense to talk anything about X-bar, because everybody's X-bar is different.
germayne: Right? Does it, does it follow so far? Like, like, if we are just saying that, oh, you know, X bar, based on the samples that we have, the votes are, Party… Party A…
germayne: Party A, Versus Party B…
germayne: you know, the vote, the X bar is the salary, the average, the average salary, etc, etc. It means nothing, right? Because X bar, like what you guys mentioned, X-bar has, like, there's so many different X-bars.
germayne: So…
germayne: you know, it's very hard to… very hard for me to reason anything about X-bar if I'm just talking about X-bar. So, the idea here is, right, end of the day, end of the day.
germayne: End of the day, You care about.
germayne: You care about mu.
germayne: Right? Agree, right?
germayne: If you were to go and do a survey.
germayne: Your survey's objective is not to care about X bar.
germayne: Your survey's objective is to care about meal.
germayne: So, the idea here is that, back to Noel's question.
germayne: is there any way for us to describe how good or bad the X-bar is, right? So, we're going to think of some way to link X-bar back to mu, and we're going to use something called confidence interval.
germayne: I'm sure some of you might have already heard of that, and might already guess that I'm going to talk about that. So I'm going to talk a bit about confidence interval.
germayne: So the idea is confi- the idea of confidence interval.
germayne: So the idea of confidence interval here is that I want to think of a way to relate what I'm making, what I calculated from X bar, to the population nu. And what I'm going to do is I'm going to exploit the property that we know from CLT. So this is going to be a bit
germayne: I mean, this is… if you guys want to know this, then you can know this, but if you guys don't want to know this, you can, you know, don't really need to understand this, but this will actually link
germayne: confidence interval.
germayne: Sorry, this will actually link what we learned from CLT back to confidence interval. So, confidence interval, later on, you will see that it allows us to reason about
germayne: you know, the quality of our X bar to some extent, and it allows us to link back to the population mean, right? Which is the thing that we are interested in.
germayne: So mathematically, right, just now, if you guys remember, I said that X bar, because of CLT, we know that it must be normally distributed with mu.
germayne: And because of the standard error, I'm going to put S over… Scrabble in.
germayne: So this is the thing that we know because of CLT. This is…
germayne: Equation 1, and we know it's from CLT.
germayne: Right? And then, if you remember just now in the slide, I introduced the standardization.
germayne: So what does that mean? It means that I can convert
germayne: I can apply a kind of transformation.
germayne: But, my iPad is lagging.
germayne: So I can actually apply a kind of transformation
germayne: Basically, to standardize these. So basically, if I'm just doing some kind of data manipulation, I'm just manipulating the equation.
germayne: And I know that these must be…
germayne: Standard normal, right? I can basically apply this. And if you think about this from the curve perspective, because you guys remember, we learned about the normal distribution curve, right?
germayne: So, we must know that it must be a bell curve, and because it's 0, 1,
germayne: We know that the center is going to be at zero.
germayne: Okay? And typically, right, typically for the normal distribution, what we are going to do, right.
germayne: What we are going to do is we are going to apply this, this… this thing called the… the… the… the…
germayne: confidence interval.
germayne: So imagine we have some kind of interval here, and because, if you remember, one of the properties I mentioned earlier on is that the normal distribution, anything under the area is what? What was the thing that is under the area of the normal distribution?
germayne: Under the curve, what is it?
germayne: What's the email?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: 50 density.
Zac Ang: relative property.
Lik Hong Eng: Well, these teams.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Public Distribution.
germayne: No, so what is this? What is this area here?
Zac Ang: Cumulative probability.
germayne: Exactly, so basically it's a probability, right? So it tells us about the probability or something. So now, right, usually in confidence interval, people always say, like, oh, you know, there's some 95% confidence interval. So what I'm going to… what I'm going to show here, right, is that we know that this equation, this equation, if I draw this bell curve out, right, it's essentially this equation.
germayne: Okay, I'm just gonna write these again, huh? So it's like…
germayne: So imagine this point, at this point, I'm going to call this… Z.
germayne: Z alpha over 2, sorry, yeah, let me draw it better.
germayne: So on the x-axis, it's going to be Z, because this is the z-score, right? So we are on the Z curve, so this is going to be Z alpha over 2, this is going to be negative Z alpha over 2. So, equation-wise, right, if you look at the curve.
germayne: Let's suppose that the area here is 0.025, and the area here is 0.025. So what this means is that the remaining area is 0.95.
germayne: Yeah, correct, right?
germayne: So, I intentionally created an area where the whole probability in the middle is 0.95, the two shaded regions out is 0.025, right? If I sum up them, they are 0.5, the whole area, it must be summed to 1, that's what I mentioned, correct? So, if you look at this, right, I'm going to write the whole equation that is related to the graph.
germayne: Because you guys said that it's a cumulative probability, right? So essentially, this formula, this curve, is going to look something like that. I'm saying that…
germayne: Okay, let me replace this.
germayne: So basically, right, the curve that I just drew is the same equation that I just wrote. Basically, I'm saying that
germayne: the Z standard… the standard… the standardized data between the probability between these two z-score, which is these two.
germayne: it must be 0.95, which is exactly this. This is a probability, right? Correct? This is exactly what I'm writing. What I drew is exactly what I'm writing as a probability. We're just describing that, right? And we are here because of this.
germayne: Okay? So now what you're going to do is you're going to manipulate… you're going to manipulate this equation. I'm not going to spend so much time manipulating the equation, I'm just going to show you guys the final outcome. So if you… if you do some basic, algebraic manipulation here, right, I'm going to shift it such that the probability is going to become like that.
germayne: So I'm going to have X bar at the side, minus Z alpha over 2 over square root n, multiplied by S,
germayne: So, you see, right, nothing changes, I'm just manipulating the equation.
germayne: But you know… can somebody tell me that… what do you notice in this equation now?
germayne: What do you notice from here? Anybody notice this?
germayne: What's the… what are we getting out of this equation? What does this equation mean?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Ding…
Gwen Lim: Isn't it a Python range?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: With the mule.
germayne: Exactly, so you notice there's a range, right? And you notice mu is in the middle. So what we are saying is that the probability of mu… oh, sorry.
germayne: What we are saying here is the probability of mu between these two range, It's going to be 95%.
germayne: Right? So essentially what I'm trying to say here is that if somehow you can calculate this guy and this guy, and give a range, so essentially the formula becomes like that, right?
germayne: The formula is not important, by the way. You guys don't need to know, but I'm just giving the intuition.
germayne: Right, so if I'm saying that the range between this and this is equals to the probability of 95%, what this means is that 95% of the time, this range will contain the
germayne: population.
Bhupinder Kaur: If you were to re…
germayne: If you were to repeat this experiment 95% of the time, of course you won't, you only do the experiment once, but the point here is that you're trying to convey that if you were to hypothetically repeat this 100 times, if you're going to do this experiment 100 times, 95% of the time, this range would contain mu.
germayne: And it's a very, very powerful statement, because you don't know mu, and this is actually what people call the confidence interval.
germayne: Now, back to the example of the election. So now, if I don't even need to calculate the whole Singapore, basically, if you can just calculate
germayne: the average, and you can just calculate, you know, using… these are all formulas that you can just plug in. Essentially, you plug this in, you calculate the confidence interval, you can say that, oh, I have this 95% confidence interval. And again, right, to interpret this, this basically means that if I were to repeat the experiment.
germayne: N number of times.
germayne: 95% of the time.
germayne: This interval will contain the
germayne: population data. So you know that 95% of the time, the population will be contained inside, but you do not know where it is, and the point is that you do not need to know where it is. You will never ever know what mu is, but you can at least make some kind of inference on where mu will be.
germayne: In terms of the range. Now, I want to ask you guys one last question before we move on from confidence interval.
germayne: You notice that I intentionally set it to 95%. It's a very, very common convention to set it to 95%.
germayne: Now, if I want to set it to 99%, I want to create a range that 99% of the time it contains meal. My question to you guys is, will the range be bigger, or will the range be smaller?
germayne: Think before you answer, huh?
germayne: I'll repeat again.
germayne: In this example, I set 95%.
germayne: If I were to create a range to contain 99% of the time, It contains the population mu.
germayne: The question is that, will the range be bigger than 95%, or smaller than 95%?
Zac Ang: Smaller.
Josiah Ho: 5%.
germayne: So, this is for the 95%, let's say the range is… let's say the mu… okay, I draw the number line, so, let's say mu is here.
germayne: The range we created is like that.
germayne: This is for the 95%.
germayne: My question is for 99%.
germayne: The range you expect to be smaller, or will the range be bigger?
Gwen Lim: The range is smaller because 99 percentile means that it has to encompass more of the majority, right?
germayne: So, Gwen and Josiah, you guys are saying that the… so if I were to create one for 99%, you are saying that you'll be smaller?
Josiah Ho: I'm saying that it should be bigger because it encompass more.
germayne: Okay, okay, I think you guys get it really correct. So the answer is, you know, it will be bigger, because.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I thought it should be bigger, too.
germayne: Yeah, it will be bigger, because now you're saying that 99% of the time it will contain, so it needs to be bigger, right?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah.
germayne: Yeah, exactly. So, okay, then you guys got it already.
germayne: Okay, so that's an intuition. So then, Noelia does… I hope that answers your question.
germayne: So…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, I guess it's like a way to…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: the thing that you can… you can link the… the X bar with the mu, so…
germayne: Correct, exactly.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, I think that's the key, lah, because I was also…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I mean, I read, but then I still don't quite understand, so until someone starts teaching it, I'm like, whoa, okay, okay, I know what you're talking about.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah.
germayne: So the idea here is that I can do all this, so if you look at what I just did from all these, from step one to step, the only reason I can do that is because
germayne: the X bar is a normal distribution, otherwise we can't do anything. So, in a sense, because we understand the underlying distribution based on central limit theorem, we can now think about the confidence interval.
germayne: Right? And confidence interval is important because it allows us to
germayne: discuss about your X-bar, and of course, you might not want to talk about X bar, now you want to talk about range, right? You want to talk about this range, and you notice, if you look at the formula, by the way, if you guys want to, like, drill in… Okay, and the reason I want to show the math is that it's not important, okay, just to tell you guys, right?
germayne: the math is not important in a sense whereby you're not going to go home and think about this math. Anyway, when you're writing the program, everything is going to be done for you. But the thing to appreciate here is that you notice that this is a…
germayne: this value…
germayne: this margin of error, we call this the margin of error, it's X bar minus… so you're talking about the X bar minus some value, and then this one.
germayne: You're taking X bar plus this value. So, essentially, it's this range that your X-bar created.
germayne: If you guys can see, it's an X bar minus… to X bar plus.
germayne: So this is the confidence interval that you create around your X bar. So you have X bar.
germayne: You have the lower limit, the lower, lower range.
germayne: And you have the upper range.
germayne: And this allows you to think about
germayne: You know, from a… from a meal perspective, does it contain the meal? Because ultimately, your goal is to reason about meal, your goal is not to reason about X bar.
germayne: So that is the first use case, using confidence interval.
germayne: Okay, I hope, I hope that is in… I believe probably everybody learned this in Poly, JC,
germayne: I can't really remember. It's been very long already, yeah.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I guess.
germayne: Yeah, I can't… I can't remember, but I'm sure you guys learned that in school somehow, but maybe back then the intuition might not be very clear, because you're just.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah.
germayne: Yeah.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Because, like, I was asking the, like, my question was, it's not like I do not know, but it's just, I just realized that when you're teaching, I said,
Low Keng Teck, Noel: There's something missing here, but I thought I understood, but I realized I didn't, so… Yeah. Yeah, so I thought I might know, but actually I didn't.
germayne: But that's a good… that's a good…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I mean, it's an intuitive thing now, so I thought I got it, and almost, yeah, then, when you're teaching, how come, like, something that's a… cannot connect, so… Yeah, that's why maybe it's been there all the while, but I never asked, so now I'm done.
germayne: Okay, yes, yes, thanks, Noel. Yes, Zach, you want to ask something?
Zac Ang: So, so now that you have done this, right, so, because it's on the standard distribution, the standard normal curve, so when you find out that, the 95% is from this number to this number, then you can say that you are sure that your population mean is from here to here.
Zac Ang: Cor… is that… is that what you're saying?
germayne: With, yes, with 95% confidence.
Zac Ang: So if I say I want to be 100% confident that my… or as close to… so 90… if I want to be 99% confident, and then you expand the range, then you're just putting in more numbers.
Zac Ang: So, what is the purpose of doing that?
germayne: Because you want to be very sure, mah. No, but it won't be very big, okay, it will be very big, but I don't think it's, like, covering… it still has a problem, it still has a range, because ultimately it's based on X-bar, right? It's based on your sample, you went out to sample the data, right?
Zac Ang: So, so, so if I convert it back to numbers, it's like, it's like I'm saying, it's like, if I'm 90… 95% sure that the average salary is between
Zac Ang: $1,000 to $2,000, then you're saying… then I'm making it 99% confidence, then it becomes… I'm 99% confident that your salary is going to be from $1 to…
Zac Ang: $10,000, something like that. It's like, I'm just making it bigger, like, how does that benefit us?
germayne: not sure if I have an answer to that. So I think… I think if you notice the formula, right, it depends on your data. All of these, the S is actually your standard deviation for your… for your sampled data. The N here, I think, is your… your…
germayne: N here, and here. Yeah, I think the N here is your size of your sample, right? And your X bar is also your sample data. Of course, if your sample is really damn tiny, damn small, your margin of error is going to be bigger, because your variance is much higher.
germayne: So, if you sample… if you sample a significant amount of people, I don't think the interval will be super, super bad.
germayne: If that's the point. I think basically, Zach, you're just saying, like, if I just go for very high confidence, right, then my range might be super, super big, right? I don't think that's necessarily true, that depends on your data. Because ultimately, here, it depends on who you are sampling, what you are sampling. If today your sample size only got 2, right, then probably your margin of error will be very big lah.
germayne: You get what I mean?
Zac Ang: Okay. Yeah.
germayne: Okay, so that's the intuition. So, the point here, right, the takeaway, right, shouldn't be that today you think that you can go out and sample with very small sample. That shouldn't be the takeaway. The quality of all of these, right, still depends on your sample sizes.
germayne: If you have very big sample size, obviously, there's strength in your… and later on, you'll see in hypothesis testing, actually, your sample size matters.
germayne: Because in companies, right, let's say when we do the A-B test, it's not like, I just run for one day and I'm done.
germayne: There's actually a minimum sample for you to reach certain statistical properties.
germayne: If that, if that makes sense. So, the point to take away here, right, is not that, oh, you know, just because normal distribution, that's why I can just, I can just anyhow do 10, you know, 10 people, 20 people. You can't. The quality of your inference depends on your sample sizes. Your sample size is still important.
germayne: Understand? I believe the Singapore Salary Guide, I think they interviewed 100,000 people, I think. 100,000 to 300,000, I believe that's a number. You might think 100,000 to 300,000 out of 6 million is small, but 100,000 still seems big, right? It's not like today you go and ask 20 people, then you think, like, oh, I know the… I know the…
germayne: I hope that gives the intuition, so, I'm not saying that sample size is not important, huh? I'm not saying that.
germayne: Still very important. The bigger sample sizes you have, the better.
germayne: Alright.
germayne: Okay, make sense?
germayne: Okay, sorry, so I digress so we are talking about confidence interval, now we'll talk about the mid.
germayne: Which is the hypothesis testing. So, the idea is actually very similar. So, the whole thing is that we are going to go… we are going to go, use the same property of the…
germayne: We're going to use the same property of the… the… the central limit theorem that we have, so I want to reiterate again. So central… okay, so now we are going to go through this thing called hypothesis testing.
germayne: Okay? So, confidence interval, Allows you to…
germayne: make some kind of inference about how many percent, what's the probability that your range will contain nu? That's what confidence interval does.
germayne: Hypothesis testing, right, you're asking the question in a different way. You're asking the question where, hypothetically, if I have some kind of mu, does my data tells me that that meal is true? So usually, hypothesis testing, right, if you guys remember, right, the equation looks something like that.
germayne: You know?
germayne: So hypothesis testing, right, how it usually works is that you assume that there's some kind of mule you want to infer. So let's say I do not know what that mu is. I want to make a guess to mu 0.
germayne: Your first hypothesis you can set to be that, okay, I think mu… I'm going to assume mu to be mu 0. My alternate hypothesis is going to be mu not equals to mu 0. So basically, the idea here is similar, right? You don't know the mu, but this mu, basically, some any value you can set can be, like, 50…
germayne: If Soria?
germayne: Don't know why the app is lagging.
germayne: So basically, right, the idea here is you can set any arbitrary number for your mu. And what you want to do here is you're going to use that same methodology, very similar, you're going to use the bell curve in order to make some kind of guess whether it's true or not. So it's just… you can think of it as a different way to answer some kind of hypothesis, that's why it's called hypothesis testing.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: I'll talk a bit about hypothesis testing, then I'll tell you guys where… what is it normally used for. So, in tech companies,
germayne: I would say we sometimes use confidence interval, but most of the time we do hypothesis testing to test whether if the… based on the experiment, based on the limited sample, if the data that we observe, does it have the effect or it does not have the effect? If the difference between control treatment is… if it's significant or not, okay?
germayne: So again, right, the math, the story is like that. I'm going to tell you guys a story. So the story starts like that, okay? You have X bar.
germayne: You know X bar follows, mu.
germayne: And it follows,
germayne: Okay, I'm just gonna write this lah. Okay, so this is basically… again, this is because of CLT.
germayne: You know X bar follows that.
germayne: Right? So what you want to do here, right, is that you assume that this is true. How it works is you assume this is true.
germayne: I don't know whether true or not, but I assume this is true.
germayne: Okay? So when I assume this is true, right.
germayne: what this means is that I'm going to set the… I'm going to set my data to be… I'm going to set… I'm going to set my data to be like that.
germayne: So far, can follow? Because I assume mu is true, alright? I assume mu must be mu 0. So, if mu is mu zero, then the equation must be like that, right? So what I'm going to do is I'm going to do the standardization again. I'm going to convert them to standard normal.
germayne: Right? So I get this formula. So assuming that mu is true.
germayne: I'm going to have a curve.
germayne: And because mu is true, mu zero.
germayne: The center must be mu 0. Okay, of course, in this case, it's 01 lah. It's 01.
germayne: Let me correct myself, huh?
germayne: 0. But this is assumed.
germayne: mu, Equals to new 0.
germayne: Right?
germayne: Now, what you want to do is…
germayne: you have your data, what, right? You have your X bar and whatever, and if mu is true.
germayne: You can actually calculate this value and see where does it appear on the curve.
germayne: So let's say, for example, your mu is like that. You calculate
germayne: This value, this one… by the way, this thing that I circled, you can calculate it, and this value depends on your… your… your sample, correct? X bar minus mu, mu 0 is a value that you want to test, so let's say it can be 50.
germayne: Right? So then, X bar…
germayne: minus 50 divided by, S divided by square. This one you can calculate. So once you calculate, right, you will get a point on your curve. So let's say this is the thing that you calculate.
germayne: Calculate.
germayne: So, there will be a corresponding area.
germayne: So you calculate it here.
germayne: And here, right, we assume that mu is true. So the idea is actually very simple. The idea is, right, there's an alpha that you will set. I don't want to go into too much detail, because I think it will kill you guys with too much context, but if on Saturday you guys are very, very interested, I can go even deeper. But essentially, you can set this thing called alpha, and usually people set it at 0.05.
germayne: Right? What alpha is, is basically your type 1 error. I'm not going to go too deep lah, okay? It's just a type 1 error. So typically, typically, people always set 0.05.
germayne: That's why your convenience interval is also 95%, so here it says 0.05. So what it means, right, is that, actually, on your curve.
germayne: there's going to be a Z,
germayne: alpha, which is equal to 0.05. And if you guys remember, right, I'm not sure if you guys remember, in the past, when you… when you do this in… in school or something, there's actually a book for you to refer. I'm not sure if you guys remember, there's this book for you to check the Z value, right? Basically, this is exactly the thing.
germayne: There's a corresponding Z value here, and usually it's the 1.96 lah. If you guys remember the value, usually it's the 1.96, or something like that. So basically, there's a Z… wait, actually, you know, 0.05… yeah, I think it's 1.96. I believe, I think it's 1.96.
germayne: Okay, I can't remember lah. Not important. But basically, there's a corresponding value here, right? You check in the book. So basically, right, the idea here is very simple.
germayne: if the… if the value… this value that you set, right, follows the alpha, is basically… you think of it like your threshold. It's a threshold that you determine yourself, and this threshold is where you say that
germayne: If the threshold do not cross my probability, Right, then I…
germayne: I do not reject the null hypothesis.
germayne: Right? But if the area is actually very small, it's actually smaller than my threshold.
germayne: then I will reject the null hypothesis, because
germayne: This curve is the distribution where the null hypothesis is true, right? If you look at it.
germayne: This is the now hypothesis. I say that this is true. So, if this is true.
germayne: Basically, the data that I calculated
germayne: should be coming from the distribution, but if the data is not coming from the distribution, then it must mean that the null hypothesis is not true, right? Because my data is not supporting it.
germayne: That's the concept. So basically, the purple line here is like, okay, this is my minimum threshold.
germayne: If the data that I calculated based on this, this is from your own data, X bar minus 50 divided by S divided by square root n, it comes from you. And if you were to go and use this data, which is your data.
germayne: And your data is actually coming from here.
germayne: then basically, you can see that the area here is actually smaller than your… so, and this is what we call the p-value lah.
germayne: The p-value from your data.
germayne: And if the p-value from our data is actually very tiny, so the intuition you follow with me,
germayne: you have a threshold that is fixed in this example, and you have some kind of area that you calculate from your data. If the area that you calculate from your data doesn't meet this threshold.
germayne: And the p-value usually here is, we set 0.05.
germayne: Right? If your area is actually very small, then basically you say that this is not true.
germayne: Because I do not have evidence that… and… and this is… this is Scenario 1, huh? Scenario 1.
germayne: So basically, your area is smaller than the critical point. So basically, I reject H0?
germayne: Because I have no evidence that
germayne: that the data is telling me that the mu is 50, because when I assume that mu is 50,
germayne: I couldn't even… I couldn't even… I couldn't even meet the critical point.
germayne: Now, scenario 2.
germayne: Scenario tour?
germayne: Scenario 2, same thing, you do the same. You calculate your X bar minus the hypothetical mu. Let's say this is 50.
germayne: divided by S square root n, you calculated this, this one turns out to be here.
germayne: And your critical point?
germayne: You set alpha equals to 0.05, you set it here.
germayne: I don't know what this val- I can't remember what this value is. So this is your critical region. Now, from your data, from your data, you calculated.
germayne: This is the red area.
germayne: Now, your red area has crossed the critical region, correct?
germayne: This is the critical point that you set. So now, once it's cross-ready, what are you saying? You're actually basically saying that, oh, my data actually has evidence. It's actually coming from this distribution, right? You see, it's a lot. So it's actually coming from this distribution. And what distribution is this?
germayne: This is a distribution that the null hypothesis is true, so here you do not reject. So here the action is…
germayne: do not… Reject.
germayne: No.
germayne: So… so you… so you do not reject that now. So basically, whatever noun that you define, okay.
germayne: I have… I… based on the data, I do not reject the null. Mu 0 must be equals to 50.
germayne: I'm just giving an example here lah, okay? I think there are some new ones that I'm missing out, because there's the right tail, left tail, one sample, two sample, but the point here is that I'm introducing this thing called the p-value. The p-value is basically the area that you are calculating based on your data.
germayne: If you guys, if you guys know what I mean.
germayne: Okay, I'm sure you guys might find this familiar lah. You guys, if you remember in school, you have to check this table. The table will tell you where the critical region would be.
germayne: And… If you look at the critical region, right, this one, and this one, this whole area.
germayne: Usually, if you set your alpha to be 0.05, it's actually 0.05 or so. Here, this whole area is 0.05.
germayne: So this whole area, this one, the green one, is 0.05.
germayne: So what this means is that usually how I remember is this is your alpha, right?
germayne: If your, if your, if your calculated p-value Ends up here.
germayne: You reject.
germayne: If your p-value ends up here, You do not reject.
germayne: Right? But if… but if you see, right.
germayne: You can just apply this without understanding, but if you understand this, the idea is just basically saying that if your area is actually very small, smaller than the critical region, then you should not be confident that your data point is actually coming from the case where the null hypothesis is true.
germayne: That's basically the idea. That's the takeaway for here.
germayne: Okay? Of course, there's a few nuance, here that maybe I can find some time to discuss with you guys on Saturday, but I think it's a bit more, it's a bit more… more…
germayne: complex. So, essentially, the next step would be that you have alpha.
germayne: You have alpha. Actually, there's also another thing called beta.
germayne: And there's also another thing called the sample size. So essentially, when you do an experiment, you can design one that the sample size is big enough for you to collect your data. So it's not like… it's not, like, randomly decided that, okay, I think 500,000 works.
germayne: Yeah. Okay, Zach, yes?
germayne: Zach, Zach, I think you're on mute.
Zac Ang: Oh, I wanted to ask why… why is… why do you say alpha?
Zac Ang: is also… Type 1… type 1 error. I don't understand that part.
germayne: No, so the definition of alpha is your type 1 error.
germayne: That is basically what your alpha is.
germayne: is the probability of you making type 1 error, but I don't want to go too deep, because it will confuse everyone. So basically, the definition of alpha, right, is the probability of me making type 1 error.
germayne: And definition of type 1 error is the probability of reject now, when… Now is true.
germayne: Okay, that's the definition. But… but… let's say in normal rule of thumb, right, people usually set the alpha to be 0.05, so 5% chance of making type 1 error.
germayne: 5% chance of me rejecting null hypothesis when the null hypothesis is true.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: And of course, the idea here is you want your alpha to be as small as possible
germayne: Yeah, of making type 1… making less Type 1 error. But I don't want to go into there, okay? I'll talk about that on Saturday if you want to know more. On Saturday, I'll talk more. So there's a relationship between the alpha, the beta, and the sample size.
germayne: So basically, you… in typical hypothesis testing cases, you have to decide the alpha, the beta, and the sample size.
germayne: But now, in this case, I just want to use this to introduce the definition of p-value. So if you go to interview, right, by the way, right, when I interview, right, my team, we usually ask people this kind of questions. What is the p-value?
germayne: So, if you are doing, like, analytical work for, like, experiments and stuff, usually you need to know this very well.
germayne: Right? So…
germayne: again, right, the p-value, the takeaway here is the p-value is basically calculated from your data to know whether if your data is actually coming from the null distribution or not. That's actually the… what the p-value is.
germayne: Right? You're using the p-value to understand if the… if from your data, whatever you calculated, if it's coming from the now… null hypothesis, if the null hypothesis is true. It's basically the area that you calculate. I think it's the… it's actually the purple color one.
germayne: If you see her, it's the purple color Ariel.
germayne: So usually in the notebook, you will see later, when you calculate… make some calculation, they will actually give… will return you the p-value as well.
germayne: And what you need to do is to just compare that with the critical regions, which is 0.05.
germayne: So my… the green color one is set as 0.05. So.
germayne: The larger your p-value is compared to the critical point, the more evidence you have that is coming from the null hypothesis, right? Right? So if it's very big, then therefore you do not reject the null.
germayne: That's the… that is the sequence of thinking.
germayne: Okay, so this is basically hypothesis testing.
germayne: Okay, I don't think I have time to do, the notebook. We'll do it on Saturday, I think. We'll do it on Saturday.
germayne: Okay, I'll just finish up by going back to the… to the thing. Okay, so on Saturday, we'll continue the notebook.
germayne: So, okay, so you can see, the thing that I introduced you guys, right?
germayne: Okay, so the thing I introduced to you guys, right, is that, okay, so you see, if I just throw this curve out, right, it will not make sense to you. So just now, as I mentioned a story.
germayne: In hypothesis testing, you basically design two hypotheses. You have a H0 and a H1.
germayne: You always assume H0 is true, and…
germayne: this is the curve where H0 is true. So this curve will be the exact curve where H0 is true, and what you'll calculate is you'll calculate using your data, and usually we have this thing called the t-test, so the t-test, but it's basically the formula that I just showed you guys.
germayne: where you take your X-bar, You minus the hypothetical value.
germayne: And you standardize it. This is the same formula that we have been saying. So this value will give you a corresponding location on the curve.
germayne: And there will be a corresponding area as well. And what you want to determine is, if the area is actually very small compared to your threshold, which is the significance level, the alpha.
germayne: And if it's smaller than the alpha, then you know that, okay, I don't think I have the evidence or the confidence that this is true. Just think of it that way, you set the threshold.
germayne: So, obviously, you want the area to cover more, right? If the area covers more, then it means that you have evidence that the H0 is true. And therefore.
germayne: If the area is more, you will not reject. If the area is less, you'll definitely reject. Just say that, okay, there's no evidence. Therefore, I'll just take H1, because H0 is not true. I do not reject. I reject H0, and I do not reject H1, and therefore, this is true.
germayne: Right? So the idea here is actually very similar, right? Hypothesis testing allows you to not only, unlike confidence interval, where you check the meal, the actual meal, here you can test any hypothetical meal. You can test any meal that you want.
germayne: Right? And you can make some inference on the meme, so it's very, very powerful.
germayne: Okay, so you can see there's a few statistical tests. I think for today's sake, no need to talk about this, no need to talk about this. I think it's okay.
germayne: The important thing is people usually do the t-test.
germayne: Right? And most of the time, we do the two group…
germayne: we do the difference in two groups. And, I'll just briefly show you guys why we do the difference in two groups.
germayne: Okay.
germayne: Okay, so let me just… let me just end off today with hypothesis testing, huh? Vela?
germayne: So I'll just give you guys the last… the last ideal.
germayne: Okay.
germayne: Okay, so I'll just give you guys the last intuition why we do hypothesis testing. So if you guys remember the story that I just mentioned, earlier on.
germayne: I gave the story where, you know, if you want to roll out a feature, you want to have a control group.
germayne: And you want to have a treatment group.
germayne: Where both of them, expo… some, this gets exposure to the feature.
germayne: And this is just normal.
germayne: Correct? I mentioned that, right, in an experiment. So what you want to do here, typically, is we will use hypothesis testing, because here we have a sample.
germayne: Size?
germayne: Usually, we expose this to some traffic of consumer, maybe, like, 10, 20% of the user, right? And here, we have the rest of the user, so maybe 80%.
germayne: So what we usually do is we want to do a hypothesis testing that is called the two-sample test. So the example that I explained on top, right, this is just a one-sample test. So the hypothesis testing called the two-sample test, and if you guys remember in school, right.
germayne: The two sample tests is basically the one with two sides.
germayne: So basically, you test 0.025 here, and you test 0.025 here. But the point is not… not important, okay? So this is the two-tail test for two… and we do it for two sample.
germayne: So, in typical companies, when we do A-B tests.
germayne: Where hypothesis testing is used is that we usually want to understand
germayne: Is there a difference between this group and this group?
germayne: Right?
germayne: We can calculate the difference in terms of the business metric.
germayne: let's say click-through rate, we can calculate that, but I want to know whether if there's a chance that it's just by chance. And what I do, what we'll do is typically we'll design a hypothesis testing that is like that.
germayne: Ugh.
germayne: So what we'll do is we'll take the difference between the two groups.
germayne: And we'll check whether if there's an effect. So basically, you look at what I'm writing.
germayne: mu1 and mu0, right, each one belongs to each group. So, control has mu 0,
germayne: And treatment has mu1.
germayne: And what we are trying to say is, I'm setting up a hypothesis test to test whether if there's an effect, and my alternate hypothesis is…
germayne: So this one basically say that there's no difference, and this one basically says there's a difference. Now, my question to you guys is, in a tech company, if you were to roll a feature, would you want H0 or would you want H1?
Zac Ang: each one.
germayne: Exactly. Because if it's HDR, it means that, oh man, actually, actually there's no effect at all, what you see is just by chance.
germayne: Right? Whatever feature that you roll out doesn't have any difference between the two groups.
germayne: So that is how hypothesis testing is used.
Gwen Lim: Can I ask a question?
germayne: Of course, of course, go ahead, go ahead.
Gwen Lim: So, so this, right, hypothesis testing can also be used in, potentially, placebo effect in drug trials?
germayne: Yes, yes. For clinical trials, they usually do this as well.
germayne: Yeah, they usually do this. So usually in… in biomedical, usually they do a lot of statistical tests, yes.
germayne: Yep. So usually when they publish their papers, they usually have all these, statistical tests.
germayne: published in the, in the, in the, in the papers. Yeah, so yes, you're right that…
germayne: There's a few, there's a few disciplines that does a lot of statistical tests. Medicine, I think, I think, medicine is one. I believe, psychology as well. I think psychology, they do a lot of study, they also do a lot of statistical tests, right? I'm sure you guys, you guys agree. I came from an economics background, so in economics, we do a lot of this in policies.
germayne: Right? So when you do policy, you want to understand if your policy has certain effect.
germayne: So you do a lot of these kind of statistical tests.
germayne: Okay? So actually, it's quite interesting, right? So the takeaway here is that if… even if you guys don't do the hypothesis test, the takeaway here is that
germayne: we are somehow able to use the central limit theorem in order to reason about the… the population's mean. And just to be very clear, everything here we are all doing about mean. If it's not mean, we cannot do any hypothesis there. So the metric
germayne: the thing of interest here has to be all of your meal, because everything is all talking about meal, right? You can see everything is talking about meal.
germayne: So everything is talking about your averages.
germayne: Right? So, yeah, of course, there are other tests to test for P50, there are other methods to go beyond the mean, but that's out of… that's out of, out of cost.
germayne: Okay? But fundamentally, if you just want to do mean, it's very easy, because the assumption's all met.
germayne: That's the takeaway. Okay, so I think… I think… I don't think I can finish, the notebook today, so probably we will wrap up, part 3 on Saturday, but part three, we will just basically be running the hypothesis test that we described today. So this is the theory side. I'm not sure whether if you guys won the…
germayne: Do you guys want the draft that I just drew?
germayne: anybody find it in, of interest, or if you guys have the recording, then it doesn't matter. Oh, so some people want. Okay, then I will just… I will just share whatever I drew. Yeah.
Hitesh shah: And where's the presentation?
germayne: Presentation, I will upload. Presentation, I will upload as well.
germayne: Yeah, don't worry.
Hitesh shah: Thanks.
germayne: Yeah, you will get the presentation, but yeah. Okay.
germayne: I'll upload that to that, yeah.
germayne: Okay, I think… I think that's all for today. I think 3, we'll probably do it on Saturday lah. I think we have time on Saturday. Let's do that on Saturday.
germayne: Then, yeah.
Bhupinder Kaur: Do we need to do Slido for today?
germayne: Yeah, you know what? I realized that I don't think I have the… like, oh wait, wait, wait, wait, let me check
germayne: Let me check if I have the Slido. I forgot about the Slido, yes.
Bhupinder Kaur: Feng will always remind you, that's funny.
germayne: Yeah.
germayne: Nowhere, I don't… let me see, huh?
germayne: I don't think I have the Slido, though.
Bhupinder Kaur: You can do on Saturday itself.
germayne: No… Combined? Wait
germayne: Give me, give me one minute, give me one loop.
germayne: Yeah, I think I forgot about the slide, though.
germayne: Saturday class has per normal till 12. Wait, yes, only by till 4pm?
germayne: Oh, okay, I think, I think I might have a side note. Let me see,
germayne: Yeah, there is Submit.
germayne: No, I don't think I have access to it.
germayne: Yeah, I don't think I can locate.
Shumin Lai | NTU: Do you need the… credentials.
germayne: Okay, yeah, just give me… I think Feng is… Feng is giving… Okay, in the meantime, anybody has any questions?
germayne: For me, while the Slido is coming back.
germayne: Okay, I hope, right, today it gives you some intuition on, basically, when people talk about applying stats.
germayne: fall…
germayne: applying stats for, like, some of the… some of the work. I hope that at least you guys have some kind of insights on, you know, what does it mean that people do. Of course, in theory, right, in theory, in theory, whatever that I've shown you guys, you don't really work out the math.
germayne: Because it's all in the library. So it's just really more of understanding. And it will kind of be similar to each of the subsequent modules, right? That, if usually, if it's me, if I'm the one teaching, then you guys have to get ready, because usually I'll give you the math parts.
germayne: But the idea here is that the math just allows you to understand the underlying concept. But when you, when you do the code right, I can rest assured that you're not writing the math.
germayne: But having the understanding is, of course, helpful, right? When things doesn't work, you're able to understand fundamentally why and stuff.
germayne: Okay, so…
germayne: having said that, I believe you guys understand. The principle for me is to always have the strong foundation for each of these concepts. So, yeah, so I think hopefully that gives you guys some of the insights on
germayne: what these topics are, especially for probability. Yeah. It's not really directly related to subsequent module, not… not completely, but this is just one portion for experimentation. Yeah, so if you're joining a company that does experimentation, they'll definitely ask you guys some of these… some of these, questions.
germayne: Yeah.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Sorry, I have one question. Just now, you say, the p-test, H0 and H1. One is equal to 0, the other one not equal to 0, what?
Chieh Cheng Lai: I'm not so clear why just now you say H1 is, I mean, most of the people will intend to see the result.
Chieh Cheng Lai: H1 do not equal zero.
germayne: Oh, okay, okay, okay, wait on, give me a while.
germayne: Okay, beta.
germayne: Let me, let me share, you know?
germayne: Just… I'll just go… I'll just answer that question real quick before I share. I have a Slido already, by the way.
germayne: Okay, so just to be clear, right, in this example.
germayne: H0 and H1, right, just basically means the… so this is the null hypothesis, this is the alternate.
germayne: Right? So in this case, what I'm just trying to do is I'm just trying to say the difference between the two mil is equals to zero. So what this means is that there's no difference between them.
germayne: So, if my group that I have exposed, this is the group that I don't have any changes, this is the group that I have changes. If the difference between the two of them is zero, what does that mean, it means that there's nothing, right? So basically, whatever that I have just introduced has no effect at all, which is a bad thing.
germayne: If you think about it, I want them to have a difference.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Oh, okay, I might not understand, no.
germayne: Right? So imagine… imagine if I give Josiah some supplements. He work out.
germayne: And then he tells me that, hey, hey, Jermaine, the thing you give me is useless. There's no effect. Then basically, the supplement is useless, right? You're just taking nothing.
germayne: Yeah, so that's the ideal, yeah.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Okay, that's why it's an equals the wrong institu. Okay, I understand.
germayne: Yeah, so here I'm just saying that the difference in mean is zero. The difference between the two of them is not equal to zero. Of course, you will hope that this is the case.
germayne: Yeah.
germayne: Okay, sorry, let me go to the Slido.
germayne: Okay.
germayne: Yeah, so the important takeaway is the CLT, yes.
germayne: Oh, but I'm curious, right, I want to see, right, anybody here actually already know this, but it's just more of a refresher?
germayne: Can you guys just let me know? I'm just very curious to know. Just give a show of hands.
germayne: Like, is this, is this something that everyone has already learned before?
germayne: Of course, those that are fresher from school may be more familiar, right, I think.
germayne: Who else? Who else? Who else, who else?
germayne: Or the rest is, like, new. Okay, I think there's a bit of people that sort of remember, but I only have 4.
Bhupinder Kaur: used it in the university, but I have never applied it in my working knowledge across
Bhupinder Kaur: But stats was one of my subjects for a very long time.
Bhupinder Kaur: Yeah, but definitely forgotten, because I've never used it. In fact, I would have used more financials and maths data now more, which I maybe did not study in those data in my…
Bhupinder Kaur: education.
germayne: 50's.
Kim Meng Phoa: My third refresher… my second refresher was when I go through the… went through the Six Sigma Greenbelt screen.
Kim Meng Phoa: They're very focused on this one.
germayne: Oh, Six Sigma Process also does tests, right? Oh, yeah, yeah.
Kim Meng Phoa: It's very heavy-dee. What you mentioned, what you report today is all from Six Sigma.
germayne: Got it, got it, got it.
germayne: Hell.
germayne: apply in gambling. Oh, actually, not sure if you guys know, I think Harvard has this black… I don't know if you guys play, poker. So I think Harvard has this poker course that is all math. This is actually very, very heavy in math. There's a lot of theory in it.
germayne: If you guys play poker, yeah.
germayne: Okay, but anyways…
germayne: Okay, okay, yeah, I think the takeaway is really all from the… it's just really a stats refresher. Unfortunately, right, I don't think everything will be, like, poured over for subsequent module, except for normal distribution. So I think a lot of things on normal distribution will come back.
germayne: But, yeah.
germayne: Okay.
germayne: Okay, so what do you guys… oh, sorry, sorry.
germayne: So, which one do you think is the hardest out of the four different segments? I believe hypothesis testing, right?
germayne: Which Ocean do you guys think is the hardest?
germayne: I think, in my opinion, should be… might be hypothesis testing. I think that should be the hardest, right?
germayne: The intuition for that, I think, definitely will be the hardest.
germayne: Yeah, I would imagine that will be the hardest.
germayne: Yeah.
germayne: And believe me, I have not even gone through, like, the big deal yet. I think I was just giving a very rough idea. Yeah, I have not talked about, like, the…
germayne: Yeah, but it's okay, yeah. I think we can discuss more on Saturday.
germayne: Yeah.
germayne: I think the good thing about today's topic is that the materials are actually very easily found lah. It's actually very easily available, if you want to read. I think you guys can easily find a lot of
germayne: Examples, but probably what you cannot find is
germayne: maybe certain application, I guess, but yeah.
germayne: Yeah, yeah, I think I understand hypothesis testing is the hardest. We'll see whether, if we want to deep dive a bit more on Saturday. I think it depends on whether, if you guys want that, whether if it's a very popular thing or… or what, but we'll see, lah, we'll see, yeah.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Yeah, the code actually is the easiest, by the way. The code, everything is given to you. So, if you don't understand the concept and just apply code, right, I don't think it's a problem. Yeah, code is very easy.
germayne: Okay, so yeah, I think let's talk about the pace for today's class.
germayne: yeah.
germayne: okay, maybe you guys are actually quite strong in math, that's why I think a majority is actually able to keep up, yeah. But I think that's a good sign, that's a good sign. So probably for the remaining Module 3, maybe you guys might think it's actually not too bad.
germayne: Yeah.
germayne: I think that's a good sign.
germayne: Okay, anybody still wants to poll?
germayne: Okay.
germayne: Okay, so what do you think are the good things for you guys today? What are some of the interesting takeaways for today?
germayne: Yeah, it's a refresher, huh?
germayne: Yeah, I would imagine, probably, it will help you guys understand why certain things is important. I feel that maybe last time when we learned in school, I don't think the application focus was there, so it doesn't really feel like, why should I care about all of these concepts? And maybe that's why it doesn't click.
germayne: Right? So, I think if there's a… if there's an idea of how to apply it, I think that becomes more relevant.
germayne: Yeah, rather than just, like, oh, you know, just the formula, yeah.
germayne: Yeah, I think that's a, that's a good, that's a good thing, yeah.
germayne: Hmm.
germayne: Okay, so I think the last one before we can take a break.
germayne: So, what do you guys think, like, are some of the areas that you would like to improve on for today?
germayne: Moving forward into the class.
germayne: Yeah, I, I, I, I think it gets, it gets, it gets easier as you, as you get…
germayne: You get more familiar with it. It will become easier.
germayne: So… Yeah.
germayne: And I think… I think maybe a very big thing for me was thinking of how to explain it, I think also helped me… helped me…
germayne: become more… more clear on the concept, so, yeah.
germayne: Oh yeah, Noelia, remember to submit your Module 2,
germayne: I think you're the only one left, yeah.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay, I'll work hard on it. I will tie you after that.
germayne: No, but I think you need to submit today, I think.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Divasa.
germayne: Yeah, I think so.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Wow.
germayne: thank you in the morning already. I think you need to submit, yeah.
Kim Meng Phoa: Local question.
germayne: Oh, yes, yes.
Kim Meng Phoa: For Module 3, I don't see any quizzes or assessments inside the NTU Learning. Is there different assessment methods for Module 3?
germayne: Shumin, do you know the answer to that?
Shumin Lai | NTU: Not really, I think maybe… He will be.
germayne: Yeah, let me, let me get back, let me get back on that, Kimming, yeah. I think don't worry about it, let me get back on that, yeah.
germayne: Okay, okay, so yeah, so I think, I think hopefully today is a good refresher. Then, yeah, I think that's all, that's all for tonight.
germayne: Okay, okay, so tomorrow, I think Thursday we will introduce the… I think Thursday we'll officially kickstart the machine learning part, and Shumi will talk a bit about some of the basic… I believe it's linear regression.
germayne: So, yeah, so I think we will kickstart on the actual machine learning.
germayne: curriculum, so this is just a good warm-up. Then Saturday, we'll come back to this again, for me to finish, okay?
germayne: Alright, okay, then I think… I think that's all. Have a good night, accept Noelle. Noel, you need to submit your… your summary. Then, yeah, the rest of you, yeah, have a good night. See you guys on Thursday… on Thursday.
Easwaran Jayaraman: Good night, thank you.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Try to submit by… by end.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: But ain't Morua.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: You might…
germayne: Quite a calculation.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: by 12, right?
germayne: I was talking.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: now.
germayne: Find time to do, find time to do.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, yeah, yeah, I'll try to finish by a little tomorrow, I'll sum it up.
germayne: Yeah.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, okay, okay, okay. 30 questions.
Kim Meng Phoa: If I…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Bye.
germayne: Okay, thank you, good night, good night, bye-bye, bye-bye.
Brian Phone Myat Swe: 8.
Daniel Chan Chee Seng (Chen Zhisheng): Every…
germayne: Yes, yes, yes, Daniel. Yes, Daniel.
Daniel Chan Chee Seng (Chen Zhisheng): I just wanted to ask you a refresh of the… the null hypothesis. Now hypothesis.
germayne: Yes.
Daniel Chan Chee Seng (Chen Zhisheng): So, if the p-value is more than 0.05,
Daniel Chan Chee Seng (Chen Zhisheng): Means you reject the… you don't reject the null hypothesis.
germayne: Correct.
Daniel Chan Chee Seng (Chen Zhisheng): If it's less than 0.05, you reject the null hypothesis.
Daniel Chan Chee Seng (Chen Zhisheng): Organic.
germayne: Correct, correct. But the 0.05 can change one, depending on what you said.
germayne: Or alpha.
germayne: Yeah, but correct, what you described is on point, yeah.
Daniel Chan Chee Seng (Chen Zhisheng): So if you… if it's less than 0.05, you reject the null hypothesis.
germayne: Correct.
Daniel Chan Chee Seng (Chen Zhisheng): If it's more than zero, but you'll buy you, don't reject the 9 apologies.
germayne: Alright.
germayne: Yep.
germayne: Okay, good night, good night, Daniel.
Daniel Chan Chee Seng (Chen Zhisheng): Good night, Jereen. Thank you.
germayne: Good night, good night.
Edwin Yap: Yeah, Jermaine, just a quick one.
Edwin Yap: just not mention the assessment for Module 3, just…
germayne: Oh, great.
Edwin Yap: Module 1 and… Module 2. Sorry, the assessment, Module 2,
Edwin Yap: I think it's, like, every… after every lesson, there's 10 basic questions for Module 1 and 2.
germayne: Huh.
Edwin Yap: So I will always use it, to, like, a refresh of my memory, and towards the end, I think there's this 30 question, the module 2,
Edwin Yap: Something similar.
Edwin Yap: So I was thinking if we… if there's some simple assessments, yeah, it would be good. That's one. Then…
Edwin Yap: Will that be the… Notebook LLM…
germayne: Oh, I need to check, that one is CP Generate one, I need to check.
Edwin Yap: Correct. I know there's a lot of, we have a lot of content now, so… but if… I was thinking, if I want to put inside what I want to put, I think I would be… I don't know what to, like, generate, because I think…
Edwin Yap: You all have… you all would like to direct our thinking, so if you all generate, yeah, it would be best for us, no, that's all.
germayne: can, can, okay, I will try to see if we have, lah.
germayne: But I'm not exactly sure whether… no promises whether there is, but I'll have you see.
Edwin Yap: I know.
Edwin Yap: Ken, Ken. But thanks, I think I really like the…
germayne: Hmm.
Edwin Yap: Oh, I really like the example of the… When you mention about, like.
Edwin Yap: So is Josiah taking the supplements, whether it's not useful and useful, I think it's able to relate, because just now what you mentioned, the examples is, I think, quite a fair bit of us able to relate better, yeah. So, really, thanks for the examples.
germayne: No problem, no problem. Okay, I'm glad, I'm glad that helped, yeah.
Edwin Yap: Yeah, it did, it did. Because I think, especially H1 or H2, if there's no change, what fall we take? I think what? That one rings a bell even for Kendra and myself, definitely.
germayne: Yes.
Edwin Yap: So, it's, very… able to relate, because, like what you mentioned earlier, it's very hard to understand, maybe when I was doing my 40 days, I really don't know what they are talking about. I mean, my lecturer told me I've, I bet he have to make me pass lah, I think I filled that module lah, in order for me to move on.
germayne: Nice, so you actually got tech lah, you got tech lah, last time, probably.
Edwin Yap: doing polys, that is one of the modules, like, I think some of us took. It's just that I think it's very… not as deep as yours, because I think yours has went into a lot of the math.
Edwin Yap: that I don't really remember. It's just, generally, there are the more… the information is there, like, Type 1, I think there's type 1, type 2, as well.
germayne: Very serious, yes.
Edwin Yap: Yeah, the confidence, confidence interval, yeah, these are topics that definitely will come true, I mean, taking steps.
germayne: Correct.
Edwin Yap: Refresher, thanks.
germayne: can, can.
Edwin Yap: No problem, okay, that's all. Thank you. Don't hold you back.
germayne: Okay, good night, good night. Bye. Good night, good night.
germayne: Anyone? Anybody else? Lenton? Isaac? All good?
germayne: Okay, yeah, I closed it, yeah.